[{"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "Working in air freight can be a stressful job. How do you handle stress on the job?", "answers": ["Are you someone who can handle stress on the job? How do you manage the stressful times? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to control pressure in the workplace.", "\"I handle stress very well, and when you call my references, they will attest to this fact. When I am under pressure on the job, I focus on the task at hand and make sure not to get distracted. Staying on deadline is very helpful, and I will delegate when necessary to alleviate some stress.\"", "\"If I am feeling stressed on the job, I will take a minute to go outside for fresh air, take a deep breath, and think about what it is that is stressing me out. Usually, the answer is that I put too much pressure on myself!\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "Do you have experience working with a customs brokerage firm?", "answers": ["A customs brokerage firm is a beneficial connection for importers and exporters. Mainly, they can push goods through customs in a timely and efficient manner. Talk to the interviewer about any exposure you have had communicating with a customs brokerage firm.", "\"I have communicated with customs brokerage firms many times in my current role, and I worked in a brokerage firm earlier in my career. I took, and passed, the US Customs Broker License Exam about three years ago.\"", "\"I have minimal experience working with a customs brokerage firm; however, I understand the importance of healthy relationships with brokerages. I have a strong service background and am confident that I can successfully manage these relationships if hired by Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "Are you aware of the basics when it comes to what you can and cannot ship by air? What would you do if a customer asked you to ship something illegal?", "answers": ["When it comes to freight and logistics, there are stringent guidelines that must be followed by all employees. Assure the interviewer that you would never put Company ABC at risk by allowing an illegal shipment.", "\"If a customer asked me to ship something illegal, I would first make sure that they were aware of the potential infraction. Some people may not know that you cannot internationally ship fruits, vegetables, cigarettes, or ammunition for example. Of course, if the customer insisted on an exception, I would turn them away. Under no circumstances would I put the company at risk.\"", "\"I understand that many customers will knowingly, or unknowingly, try to ship illegal items. If a customer asked me to ship something illegal, I would provide them with the appropriate shipping guidelines and would refuse.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "What causes you to feel dissatisfied on the job?", "answers": ["Everyone will have particular triggers that cause them to feel dissatisfaction on the job. Talk to the interviewer about any factors that may deflate or discourage you in the workplace.", "\"I can feel dissatisfaction on the job when I am not feeling heard or when there is not mutual respect among the team members. I work best in more harmonious situations where there is little drama or gossip.\"", "Try turning your answer into one with a positive spin! Rather than focus on the negative, focus on what keeps you happy in your job.\n\nFor example: \"I feel happiest and most content in a positive environment where I feel appreciated. I also greatly value opportunities to develop myself professionally.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "What career path interests you the most with Company ABC?", "answers": ["This question is where it is essential to have completed some research on Company ABC before your interview. Be sure to envision where you can see yourself fitting, and growing, with the organization before your interview. Do some research on what a career path could look like with Company ABC.", "\"What interests me most about Company ABC is that there are so many options when it comes to career growth. Ideally, I would like to earn my way into an xx role, then an xx position. Eventually, an xx or xx position would be ideal. Of course, I understand that this will take many years of dedication and hard work.\"", "\"It appears there are a lot of career path opportunities with Company ABC such as A, B, and C. Do you have a specific career path in mind for me, or for this particular position?\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "In your opinion, what makes you a great problem solver?", "answers": ["Employers want to know that you have a methodical approach to problem-solving. Consider the skills and qualities that help you successfully face problems. Perhaps you have a keen eye for detail. Maybe you can see opportunity when others can only focus on the issue. Share your strengths as a problem solver, and your ability to come up with innovative solutions.", "\"I am a great problem solver because I do not allow stress to cloud my judgment and mute my creativity. I am a keen observer with a great memory which allows me to recall unique solutions or ideas.\"", "Strong problem solvers are: \n\n- Systematic thinkers\n- Open minded\n- Okay with being wrong sometimes\n- Always researching and exploring\n- Able to identify the core problem \n- Able to reverse engineer a challenge to avoid future issues\n- Able to come up with multiple avenues that work well for all stakeholders\n- Are do-ers and not worriers"]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "In the air freight industry, many things are time sensitive. How would you handle a customer who did not receive their parcel on time?", "answers": ["Customers will become quite agitated and upset when their packages are not received, delivered on time, or when they feel a bit overcharged. How do you handle an angry or dissatisfied customer?", "\"I fully understand that parcels are incredibly important to your customers and I will try to be as empathetic as possible when it comes to the needs of a customer. Keeping a calm tone is always helpful when working with dissatisfied customers. I would help them to feel heard and let them know that I will help them as much as I can.\"", "\"If a customer did not receive their parcel on time, I would follow the company protocol and procedures while also maintaining an empathetic tone to the customer.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "At Company ABC we use a robust software system for parcel tracking. Do you have experience in tracking and inventory management software?", "answers": ["Whether you have used the same software systems used at Company ABC, or not - it is crucial for you to demonstrate your ability to pick up new programs and technology. Talk to the interviewer about your technical skills. You can list the programs that you are most familiar in and be sure to talk about your level of expertise in each.", "\"I understand that you use Software A for your parcel tracking. In my most recent position, we used a similar program. I have approximately four years' experience with Software B, and would consider myself an advanced user.\"", "\"Although I do not have direct experience in inventory management software, I do have experience in customer management programs as well as team-based applications. I am technically savvy and am confident in my abilities to learn new software and programs very quickly.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "Do you have experience with challenging shipments such as temperature controlled packages?", "answers": ["Sensitive freight can be a tricky task. Talk to the interviewer about any experience that you have with packages that need extra care and attention.", "\"I have shipped some challenging and sensitive freight including temperature controlled, live animals, and fragile items. I enjoy the challenge associated with sensitive freight. If I am unsure of how to appropriately handle a package, I will not hesitate to ask.\"", "\"I may be newer to my career in air freight; however, I understand that packages such as temperature controlled shipments, or shipments containing live animals, can be a major challenge in the air freight industry. I am eager to learn more about the ins and outs of this business.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "What leadership qualities do you possess?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know if you naturally take on a leadership based attitude in the workplace. You don't have to be interviewing for a leadership or management role to be asked these types of questions. Choose three qualities, and share your perspective on why you feel you have each of these qualities.", "\"My strongest leadership qualities include my ability to actively listen, give strong feedback gently, and the fact that I am always looking for opportunities to teach and coach others.\"", "Choose from this list if you are coming up short. Some great qualities of a leader are:\n\r\n- Being someone who people naturally want to follow\r\n- Exceptional interpersonal skills\r\n- Strong relationship building skills\r\n- Taking ownership for the team's errors and mistakes\r\n- Excelling at motivating others\r\n- Providing kudos to your team\r\n- Knowing how to select and hire the right people to join the team\r\n- Having a vision for the future"]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "Tell me about your most significant work experience that relates to this position.", "answers": ["This question is an excellent example as to why it is essential for you to review the job description, in detail, before your interview. Have you ever held a similar position to this one? Can you draw any similarities between this role and another job that you have had?", "\"Three years ago, I worked for Company X in a very similar position. It required less team supervisory experience but additional educational components. The role also involved shift work and the ability to lift up to 50 lbs on a regular basis. These factors prepared me for a position like this one.\"", "\"The position that most relates to yours would be the role in which I currently work. This position with Company ABC offers more growth potential; however, the roles sound quite similar.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "In your opinion, what are the benefits of air freight?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about why you feel air fright is a good option. Keep your answer brief and positive. The interviewer wants to know that you see value in their services.", "\"I feel that the biggest benefit of air freight is the fact that you can deliver any package to any place in the world, in record time. It is a huge benefit to business, the healthcare industry, and even personal needs.\"", "\"There are many benefits to air freight and, to me, one of the greatest benefits is that air freight allows for much smoother global trade.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "At Company ABC we take proper documentation very seriously. Do you consider yourself to posses strong attention to detail?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you see value in the details. Discuss how you ensure that you meet all the essential points in your day to day activity and documentation. You can also mention a previous colleague or supervisor who may have complimented you on these skills.", "\"I am a very detail driven person, and I fully understand the importance of accuracy in this line of work.\"", "\"My current supervisor often comments on my great knack for the small details. I am sure he will comment on that when you call him for a reference.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "At Company ABC we have a strong reputation for making our customers happy. How do you ensure that your customers are always satisfied?", "answers": ["Exceptional customer service is always valuable; however, it can be especially important for Company ABC since it is such a competitive industry. Assure the interviewer that you understand how vital excellent customer service is. Give an example of a time when you went over and above for a customer.", "\"We had a customer who had a package arrive three days late. When she called in to complain, she was irate and very worked up. I was able to diffuse the situation by listening intently. I offered her a refund on her shipping costs and asked her what she would like from us in the future. Simply feeling understood, and heard, was important to her. That same customer called my manager the next day and complimented me on my service. It was a great feeling.\"", "\"I ensure that my customers are always satisfied by asking them if they are happy with my service, after every interaction. It can make a big difference when they feel that you truly care about their overall experience.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "On a scale of 1-10, how familiar are you with the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) and the rules of international shipping?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you have exposure to NAFTA and that you understand the important part that it plays in international shipping and air freight. Give yourself a rating from 1-10 and explain your answer.", "\"I attended NAFTA training through the Global Training Center in 2015. On a scale of 1-10, I would say that I am a nine regarding my NAFTA knowledge. If you have additional training in international shipping, I am happy to participate as well. You can never know too much!\"", "\"I have had to study the details surrounding NAFTA and international shipping; however, I am newer to my career in air freight. I would rate myself as a 5 out of 10. I love to learn, and I am happy to study up as much as needed.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "At Company ABC we always prefer to promote from within. Are you looking for a long term career in logistics and freight?", "answers": ["Hiring new employees is a costly and time-consuming task. If on-boarded, do you see a long-term career fit with Company ABC? Assure the interviewer that you plan to commit to the company for as long as possible.", "\"I have a keen interest in freight and logistics. I have some educational background in warehousing and logistics as well. This position is a long-term career plan for me, and I would like to stay with Company ABC as long as possible.\"", "\"I appreciate that Company ABC promotes from within, whenever possible. I am most certainly looking to join an organization that will have me for the long term, and invest in my career progression at the same time.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "Air freight is all about timeliness. How do you manage your time?", "answers": ["What tools do you use to stay on task and meet deadlines? How do you prioritize when everything demands your attention at once? Think about the ways you manage your projects and daily tasks. Perhaps you set yourself a lot of reminders or utilize the calendar on your smartphone or Outlook. Sometimes a to-do list is helpful when you're managing your time because it can help you prioritize what needs to happen next. Paying attention to which tasks require the most time and which ones bring the most value are ways you can pick and choose what needs to happen in your schedule. What are some ways you have found work best for you to manage your time at work?", "\"Each time my boss changes his schedule, I need to drop what I am doing and rearrange his meetings or travel plans. These changes happen quite often, so I very well know that a schedule made is not always a schedule kept. I stay ahead of these changes by remaining organized and leaning on the company's internal applications and CRM to organize my files and the data that I need.\"", "\"I manage my time through the use of calendar tools as well as setting priority tasks for myself, first thing in the morning. My time management skills are strong.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "What is your current salary?", "answers": ["A potential employer will often base their offer on your current salary. You should be transparent about your most recent earnings and be prepared to back up any salary requests.", "\"I am currently earning a base salary of $78,000 plus a car allowance of $900/month and health benefits. I am looking for a competitive salary in my next position.\"", "\"In my last position, I was earning $47K/year which I understand was low for my industry, level of experience, and educational background. In my next position, I am targeting a base salary in the $55K range.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "What unique qualities about yourself would you bring to our company?", "answers": ["There are some things that your resume cannot do. Showing off your fabulous personality is one of them, for instance! Talk to the interviewer about some of your unique qualities and be sure to tie these qualities into how they will benefit the company, should they hire you.", "\"I have a unique ability to strike up a conversation and build rapport with nearly anyone. This ability is a great help when it comes to customer service and sales. My up-selling percentages are always very high.\"", "Here are some ideas of unique qualities: \n\n- Strong Presenter \n- Experience Coaching Co-Workers\n- Experience Training a Software or Program\n- Successful Client Facing Experience\n- Culture Fit\n- Strong at Receiving Feedback\n- Skilled in Providing Feedback\n- Flexible Schedule\n- A Specific Creative Skill\n- Experience Developing New Process\n- History in Taking Initiative"]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "Tell me about a situation in which you had to work with fellow team members who did not like you.", "answers": ["You may sometimes come across personalities that do not mesh with yours, and that is okay! Talk to the interviewer about a time that you had to work with someone who may not have liked you. How did you handle the situation?", "\"When I first started in my current role, I was replacing a very beloved manager who had retired. My new team was not happy about the change, and they initially set out to give me a hard time. I addressed it within the first week, acknowledging that I had big shoes to fill. I believe that the team respected this honest approach and slowly everyone came around once they realized that I had their best interest in mind.\"", "\"The most recent experience I can think of was when I was attending University and had to work on a group project with a few very competitive individuals. Our personalities did not mesh well because I am more of a collaborator, wanting all of us to succeed. When I realized that it was a sink or swim type of situation, I began to make decisions that would offer me the best experience and the best grade. It was a learning experience for sure.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "Do people see you as a trustworthy and honest individual?", "answers": ["It is easy to say that you are trustworthy and honest, but it's best if you can back it up with a review or words from a previous supervisor.", "\"I am an honest and trustworthy individual, and you will be able to hear that directly from my supervisor when you call for a reference. I hold honesty and trustworthiness as fundamental virtues.\"", "\"In my 20-year career, my supervisors have always commented on my level of honesty and how much they appreciate that I am reliable and trustworthy. I believe that I am a trustworthy and honest individual.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "Considering your background is in an industry different from ours, what skills and characteristics do you have that qualify you for this position in this industry?", "answers": ["There are many ways that you can be a fit for a position, even though you do not come with direct industry experience. Think about the variety of skills that you have and how those can benefit another employer, despite the industry. These are your transferable skills, and they can include sales abilities, customer service experience, and software capabilities.", "\"Although my background is not in your precise industry, I have worked with many clients who have been in your industry. I bring excellent transferable skills that qualify me for this position. These skills include my advanced abilities in Excel, my outstanding cold-calling abilities as well as my proven background in team leadership.\"", "Here is a list of skills that can be transferable to any industry: \n\n- Exceptional communication \n- Experience learning new procedures and software\n- Public speaking \n- Negotiations \n- Delegating work \n- Training others\n- Building customer relationships\n- Developing supplier or vendor relationships \n- On-boarding and recruitment \n- Supervisory experience \n- Scheduling \n- Running meetings\n- Negotiations\n- Committee Organization \n- Clerical skills \n- Budgeting \n- Research and Reporting"]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "When entering a new job, describe how you build relationships with your new coworkers and supervisors.", "answers": ["Due to a wide variety of personalities, relationships can take time to form. How do you ensure that you have a strong line of communication with your co-workers and supervisors, right from the start?", "\"I understand that some relationships come quickly and others take time to nurture. When starting a new job all that I can do is be my true self and let my personality, integrity, and reliability speak for itself.\"", "\"I prefer to build relationships by making others feel they are important to me. When meeting new people, I will ask a question related to their area of expertise, and try to learn something from them.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "When have you had to think quickly in response to sudden change?", "answers": ["Sudden changes will occur in the workplace from time to time. Assure the interviewer that you are capable of responding quickly, and professionally, to sudden changes in the workplace.", "\"I can think quickly on the job, and I do respond well to sudden change. Last week I was asked to tweak a presentation with just 30 minutes notice. The changes were significant, but luckily I work well under pressure. The presentation went well, and our clients were delighted.\"", "\"In my current position, my schedule is often changed with very little notice. I can adapt and change my schedule around to accommodate my employer, as much as possible.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "We value our company culture at Company ABC. In your opinion, why is it important to develop relationships with coworkers?", "answers": ["This answer may seem obvious to you because enjoying your time with coworkers is sometimes the best part about the job! If you aren't a naturally social person, this question may seem more challenging to answer. \n\nTalk to the interviewer about how you develop relationships with coworkers when you start a new job. Think about what is important to you about these relationships. Do your co-workers motivate you when you feel overworked? Do your coworkers give you a reason to show up to work when your boss has been giving you a hard time?", "\"I value my relationships with my coworkers because we support each other and make each other laugh when the work environment becomes intense. I have a coworker that I eat lunch with every day. We've helped each other out by simply listening to what's going on in each other's lives. It's nice to have colleagues who understand you on a personal level.\"", "\"All of the colleagues I have worked with have shared a very respectful relationship with me. We have similar goals, and we exchange knowledge to accomplish those things to the best we can. Each of us has a part in the company's success, and we utilize communication to make it happen.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "A career in air freight requires a great deal of patience. Do you consider yourself a patient person? How do you increase your patience level in challenging situations?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you consider yourself a patient individual. Impatience can cause a lot of stress and anxiety in coworkers, so it is vital that you can showcase your ability to remain patient and professional in workplace situations. \n\nPatience is indeed a virtue but can be challenging to maintain when it seems that situations continue to push your buttons. Show the interviewer that you possess the ability to keep your cool in challenging conditions.", "\"I do consider myself a patient person. I would rate myself an eight /10 for patience because I certainly have room to grow, but I do have a very long fuse. If I need a boost of patience in a challenging situation, I will take a step away, count to 10 and then return to the situation. I recently read a book, 'The Power of Patience' by M.J. Ryan which also gave me some excellent new methods for coping under stress.\"", "\"I was once managing a group that could not quite get along, and it tested my patience a bit because it prevented us from staying on track and focusing on the goals. I went above and beyond in helping the group get along by scheduling lunches as a team and helping to mediate situations that needed it.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "If you were hired to work for Company ABC today, what would you accomplish first?", "answers": ["When you start a new position, it is essential to set a goal on how you will make a positive impact quickly after being hired. Tell the interviewer what your impact goal is, should you be the successful candidate.", "\"When we were speaking earlier, about sales targets in this position, you mentioned that most new sales professionals hit their KPI's after 120 days. If hired today, my goal would be to exceed my KPI's after the first 90 days. I plan to make a positive impact very quickly.\"", "\"If hired today, I would start with analyzing all quantifiable data from the last month, quarter, and year to identify any bottlenecks or shortfalls in productivity. I would make corrections from there. Perhaps this will be in the form of creating better processes, implementing new applications for productivity, or simplifying the vendor process. This work will, of course, coincide with your biggest pain-points at the moment.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "When planning, how often do you create alternative scenarios to help you adjust to changing situations?", "answers": ["Being able to problem solve and think outside the box when it comes to changing situations is a valuable skill set. Talk to the interviewer about your ability to create a variety of potential scenarios. You may never need to take on these scenarios; however, it's great for the interviewer to know that you can adapt your plan on the fly.", "\"I feel that it is essential to create alternative scenarios in all situations. One cannot guess what will happen in the end, so it is great to prepare for all possible outcomes.\"", "\"Alternate scenarios are great to have, but I prefer to stay focused on my desired outcome. So long as my team is on board with the goals we have yet to achieve, I am confident that we will always reach Plan A.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "Why should we hire you at Company ABC?", "answers": ["If you can't think of ways that you are unique, ask a few friends or family members what they feel sets you apart from other people. Their observations may help you understand how you are perceived.\n\nPerhaps you already know what sets you apart! This example could include any industry accolades, exceptional achievements, additional industry related training, a second language, or how involved you are in the community. Don't be afraid to brag about yourself a bit. In an interview, you are your most influential advocate.", "\"You should hire me because I am unlike anyone else you have interviewed before. When I started with my current company, I was the youngest salesperson they had ever hired. That didn't stop me from becoming the #1 sales person in the company within six months. I am dedicated to my craft and engaged in this industry to the point where I commit myself to taking at least one business development or leadership related workshop every business quarter. I am a competitive achiever. You won't be disappointed when you hire me.\"", "\"You should hire me because I'm qualified and passionate about your cause. I am excited about the idea of delivering value to your organization and will hustle for the opportunity to go above and beyond for your customers.\""]}, {"topic": "Air+Freight", "question": "Would you consider yourself a creative person?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about any interest that you have in creativity and how you have implemented that desire in the workplace. Even if you do not consider yourself to be a 'creative person,' there is a significant change that you have made creative minded decisions in your career.", "\"I do consider myself to be a creative individual. One example of this would be the telephone sales scripts that I crafted for our inside sales team. They were lively and effective, and sales increased by 23% in the first 90 days of implementation.\"", "\"I am someone who alternates back and forth with the right/left brain, but I will always consider myself a very creative person. I admire the creativity and unconventional thinking in business and arts.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "Judging by your resume, you appear to be overqualified for this position. What would keep you at Company ABC, if you were offered the position?", "answers": ["Sometimes, hiring an overqualified individual can mean that they will leave when a better opportunity arises. Talk to the interviewer about why this position would be satisfying for you, long-term.", "\"I do have more years' experience than what you have outlined in your job posting; however, there are aspects of this position that would be new and exciting for me as well. For example, I would enjoy the exposure to more enterprise accounts. Despite my level of experience, there would be much for me to learn here.\"", "\"Although I may appear to be overqualified for this role, I assure you that the work at Company ABC will offer me an exciting challenge.  Your company is larger than my current employer, and I look forward to learning how to manage the volume of work here.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "Integrity is everything to us at Company ABC. What would you do if you caught a co-worker stealing?", "answers": ["Show the interviewer that you are honest and trustworthy. Theft can be a significant factor in financial loss for a transportation and logistics company. Discuss with the interviewer how you would do your part to alleviate this issue. If you have experienced a situation like this before, you can certainly use your real-life example. Discuss how you handled the situation and what the resolution was.", "\"If I caught a co-worker stealing I would report the situation to my manager right away. If my manager were not available, I would tell the co-worker that I saw what they did and ask them to return the item. I fully believe that it is my responsibility as an employee to enforce theft prevention procedures whenever it is safe to do so.\"", "\"If I caught a co-worker stealing, I would report the incident immediately. As a previous manager, I understand the value of employee honesty.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "Tell me about a time when you failed to solve a problem. How did you overcome the failure?", "answers": ["\"Success is bouncing from failure to failure without losing momentum,\" or so they say. Your resilience shines through when you can learn from your mistakes and keep going. Give an example that shows you can accept fault and learn from challenging experiences.", "\"Success is bouncing from failure to failure without losing momentum,\"", "\"I was asked to solve our issue of employee turnover which ended up being much more difficult than I originally thought. My initial goal was to improve turnover by 70% but in the end, only reached 40% improvement. Although I did not reach my goal, I am still happy that my action plan made a difference.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "At Company ABC we use a robust software system for parcel tracking. Do you have experience in tracking and inventory management software?", "answers": ["Whether you have exposure to the same software systems used at Company ABC, or not - it is vital for you to demonstrate your ability to pick up new programs and technology. Talk to the interviewer about your technical skills. You can list the programs that you are most familiar with and be sure to talk about your level of expertise in each.", "\"I understand that you use Software A for your parcel tracking. In my most recent position, we used a similar program. I have approximately four years' experience with Software B, and would consider myself an advanced user.\"", "\"I do not have experience in any logistics specific software; however, I do have about two years' experience in tracking software like Tick and Backlog. I look forward to learning your systems.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "There are a lot of career options within the logistics industry. Why do you specifically want to work for Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that this isn't just any ordinary opportunity for you. Show your desire to work for Company ABC specifically! Your answer should reveal that you have researchedCompany ABC as well as their competitors. \n\nTo prepare, check out the company website and online reviews. Choose the aspect of their organization that stands out most to you. Perhaps Company ABC has the best online reviews in the industry. Maybe their company culture aligns well with the work environment you are seeking, or you like that they put a focus on giving back to their community. Whatever your reasons for being interested in Company ABC make sure it is evident to the interviewer that you want THIS job.", "\"I have been eager to find a place in your company for some time now. I regularly check your company careers site for opportunities. There are a few reasons why Company ABC stands out to me. The primary reasons are your great reputation and the fact that you have a healthy company culture. Your employees seem happy to be here.\"", "\"This position with Company ABC aligns nicely with my career goal of continued growth within logistics.  This role is in my comfort zone, but a new enough approach that will intrigue me, and this company size is adequate to support growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "Why is this job with Company ABC right for you at this time in your career?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer why you are looking to make a change, and how this particular role with Company ABC fits well with the changes that you are seeking. Be sure to give a more in-depth answer than the typical \"I am looking for growth\" answer that so many interviewers hear. Be thoughtful and draw upon the research you have done on the company.", "\"This is the right job for me because it is what I have been trained to do.  My education and previous work history are related to the role and the industry, making it a perfect fit.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "At Company ABC we value and reward honesty. On a scale from 1 to 10, how honest are you?", "answers": ["Do you feel that you are a sincere person or do you have room for growth? This question could be a tricky one as nobody is always 100% honest. Answer to the best of your ability and back your reply by speaking about your ethics.", "\"I would love to give myself a 10/10 for honesty but truthfully - nobody is 100% honest all of the time. I will give myself an nine because I always do my best to be as honest as possible.\"", "\"I put a heavy focus on honesty and trustworthiness in the workplace, as well as in my personal life.  Because I strive for complete honesty, I will rate myself as a 10/10. My values are solid.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "Would your former or current boss describe you as a worker who gladly goes the extra mile to complete their tasks?", "answers": ["You can say that you will go the extra mile, but it's best to give a real-life example to the interviewer about a time when you did just that. Offer up your references as well and discuss with the interviewer what you feel your most recent employer would say about you.", "\"My former boss would describe me as an employee who goes the extra mile. In my most recent position, I was always available on my email, and many of my service clients had my cell phone number just in case of an after-hours emergency. When you call my reference he will be happy to expand on that for you, I am sure.\"", "\"I sure hope so! I have always put my best foot forward, and I very much dislike being bored. I go the extra mile whenever possible because that's what great employees do! I have received very positive feedback from all of my previous employers.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "At Company ABC we prefer to hire those with some industry knowledge. Can you explain what Less Than Truckload (LTL) is?", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking for evidence that you have some basic knowledge of the logistics industry. How you answer this question will indicate to the interviewer the level of experience that you have in their industry. \n\nEven if you have not worked in the logistics industry before, you should have conducted some industry-related research before your interview. Remember, the interviewer is not necessarily looking for a full understanding of systems and processes (depending on the level of role you are interviewing for) - they may merely be looking for an indication of sincere interest in what they do at Company ABC.", "\"From my understanding, LTL carriers will transport goods from multiple companies at a time. LTL or, Less Than Truckload, means that the shipper and deliverer may reach an agreement on reduced pricing if they aren't filling an entire truck. Instead of the price being based on the whole truck, it will be calculated according to the weight of the shipment, and the distance.\"", "\"Although I am new to the logistics industry, I believe that LTL is related to the shipping of partial loads. With that said, I am here to learn. Could you take a moment to explain LTL briefly to me?\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "Company ABC offers many avenues for career growth. Where would you like to take your career with us?", "answers": ["Before your interview, be sure to visit Company ABC career opportunities online. Take note of the range of possibilities. Perhaps there are opportunities in other locations? What kind of growth is available in the particular department with which you are interviewing? Assure the interviewer that you desire a long-term opportunity with Company ABC by discussing the career path you would like.", "\"I saw a few leadership opportunities posted on your company website that seemed very interesting. Ultimately, I would like to work my way into a management role where I could lead a team. I am very interested in working for Company ABC because of the multiple growth opportunities present here, and I look forward to proving my capabilities to you.\"", "\"I would love to see myself growing into a more prominent leadership role within your organization. My career interests align very nicely with your company's goals which helps me to see a great long-term fit here.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "How would you describe your work ethic?", "answers": ["When the interviewer asks about your work ethic, they are looking for specific examples or keywords to which they can relate. When you read the company job, posting or job description do they refer to particular company ethics? Talk about the values of Company ABC and how those align well with your work values.", "\"I am a very dedicated and loyal employee. I saw on your website that you describe your company as honest, transparent and you go the extra mile for your clients. My work ethic is the same. I am honest, flexible, and come ready to work hard for my employer every day.\"", "Some characteristics you may want to use are: \n\n- Determined/Driven\n- Accountable\n- Humble\n- Respectful\n- Dependable"]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "At Company ABC we prefer to hire those with some industry knowledge. Can you tell me what Advanced Shipping Notice (ASN) is?", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking for evidence that you have some basic knowledge of the logistics industry. How you answer this question will indicate to the interviewer the level of experience that you have in their industry. \n\nEven if you have not worked in the logistics industry before, you should have conducted some industry-related research before your interview. Remember, the interviewer is not necessarily looking for a full understanding of systems and processes (depending on the level of role you are interviewing for) - they may merely be looking for an indication of genuine interest in what they do at Company ABC.", "\"Advanced Shipping Notice is an important document that the customer receives containing all of their pertinent shipping information. This notice could include specifics related to their shipment, carrier information, delivery expectations, and estimated arrival time, for example.\"", "\"Although I am new to the logistics industry, I believe that ASN is related to shipping notices. With that said, I am here to learn. Could you take a moment to explain ASN briefly to me?\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "There are a few major competitors who promise cheaper delivery than we do at Company ABC. How will you overcome this challenge with our potential customers?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you can overcome simple objections from clients. Being the cheapest solution in the market is not necessarily the best answer. Show the interviewer that you can identify the value in their service. How would you show a customer that Company ABC is the best choice for their shipping/logistics needs? To answer this question correctly, you must have conducted some research on Company ABC and their competitors. Your answer should reflect the ways that Company ABC stands out in the industry.", "\"I do not lean on price alone when I discuss shipping options with my customers. I would overcome this objection by showing the customer all of the value-added services at Company ABC such as your money back guarantee, the elevated professional environment, as well as the available 24/7 support line. I truly believe that most customers will take service and convenience over cost savings.\"", "\"I believe that the best business strategy is not to lead by price but by value. The best way to do this is to  find out what they value and need, and then show them how I can help them to meet those needs.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "Superior customer service is very important to us at Company ABC. How would you handle a situation where a customer came to pick up a shipment and you could not locate it?", "answers": ["Customers will become quite agitated and upset when their packages are not received, delivered on time, or lost. Assure the interviewer that you would always handle a sensitive customer related issue with the utmost professionalism. Walk the interviewer through the steps that you would take. Show that you are capable of problem-solving while under pressure.", "\"I fully understand that parcels are incredibly important to your customers and I will try to be as empathetic as possible when it comes to the needs of a customer. Keeping a calm tone is always helpful when working with dissatisfied customers. If I could not find the package, I would offer to locate the package and have it delivered to their home, free of charge, once it was received. If the situation needed to be escalated, I would refer to a manager for assistance.\"", "\"I am sure that Company ABC has policy and procedures in place for a situation like this. With that said, my instinct would be to keep a calm tone, and offer to deliver their package to them once it was located.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "What was your greatest cost-cutting measurement you accomplished at your previous employer?", "answers": ["If you are in a management type of role, you will often be asked to keep your eyes open for cost-saving opportunities. Assure the interviewer that you are capable of understanding the importance of this practice and give a strong example of a time when you have done so.", "\"I have been able to present cost-cutting suggestions many times to my previous employer. The one that I feel had the biggest impact was when I suggested additional warehouse staff. We had three various shifts and still an average of 100 hours of overtime per week. I presented to my employer that we hire one more warehouse employee for each shift, keeping the hours to just 120 regular vs. 100 hours of overtime pay (@1.5x) This recommendation saved the company $31,000 per year. They implemented this change across 15 warehouses the following year, amounting to nearly half a million dollars in savings per year.\"", "\"The greatest cost-cutting measurement that I accomplished at work was through new suggestions for theft prevention. Since we implemented some of my suggestions our loss, due to theft, has decreased 12%.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "How do you like to encourage ideas in others?", "answers": ["Being able to encourage others is a great skill to possess. Talk to the interviewer about your ability to promote creative ideas in your team members.", "\"I like to encourage other people to be creative in their thinking and present ideas to the company, no matter how off the wall they may seem. Some of our most successful employees are ones who are confident in their ability to bring forward their unique ideas. I encourage participation through an open door policy and strong praise for those who show initiative.\"", "\"I encourage people to tap into the best parts of themselves. It helps to ask probing questions to get them to generate ideas on their own. I have found that by painting a long-term vision for where I want to go, my team will often jump in with creative solutions to get us there.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "In your opinion, what is the most valuable service Company ABC offers small business?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see that you have done your research on Company ABC before the interview. Before your meeting, you should have a firm idea of the business solutions that Company ABC offers as well as how their IT solutions stand out from their competitors. Discuss what you think is the best of their small business solutions, and why. \n\nIf you want to keep the conversation going, it's a great idea to ask the interviewer what they feel is the best service they offer. By doing this, you are going to extra mile to show the interviewer your keen interest in Company ABC.", "\"I have reviewed all of the small business services offered by Company ABC. It's tough to choose the one I feel is best because you have so many great options. If I had to choose just one, I would say that by offering LTL rates, you are giving an amazing service to the financially discerning small business customer. What do you feel is the most valuable service offered at Company ABC?\"", "\"Although I truly believe that all of your services are equally important, I think that the way you break down analytics would be an especially important service for your small business clients.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "Do you understand our primary customer base at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Part of your research before going into an interview should include the demographic that Company ABC is trying to reach. Perhaps their customer base is made up primarily of small business owners. Or, maybe they focus only on custom business solutions for large-scale companies. Discuss with the interviewer your understanding of the customer base at Company ABC and talk about how your experience will benefit them should they choose to hire you.", "\"From the research that I have conducted, my understanding is that your primary customer base is small business owners looking for fast and affordable service, while still enjoying a personalized experience. The majority of my work experience has been with a start up companies and small business owners. This experience would be valuable to Company ABC if you choose to hire me because I am already aware of the customer experience small business owners are looking for.\"", "\"My understanding is that your primary customer base is currently medium-sized businesses but that you are now refocusing to target enterprise level businesses. Is this correct?\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "We run a variety of shifts at Company ABC since our business is a 24/7 operation. Do you have a preferred shift?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know what kind of flexibility you can offer Company ABC when it comes to your work schedule. If you have any restrictions on your calendar, this is an excellent time to address them. If there is a specific shift that you are looking for, be upfront about your preference.", "\"I am more than willing to be a flexible employee for Company ABC. Currently, I do not have many restrictions on my availability with the exception Tuesday evenings.\"", "\"For my family and personal life, I do prefer to work the afternoon shift. This shift allows me to get my kids to school, and then my husband picks them up after school. We try to stagger our hours to accommodate our children's needs.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "Give me an example of a time when you went above and beyond.", "answers": ["Display to the interviewer that you can do more than just the bare minimum. Show that you can react appropriately when you see that your employer has a need that goes beyond your usual day-to-day expectations.", "\"Last week I noticed that my manager had not completed the schedule for the following week. Some of the staff were complaining that they didn't have their work schedule yet. Rather than going to my manager with the complaint, I offered to take on some of her workload so that she would have the time to complete the schedule. We worked together for a couple of overtime hours that day and were able to catch her up on everything. It felt good to help.\"", "\"I'd like to think that I go above and beyond most days. I help out my colleagues when they are running behind. I work overtime hours when they are requested of me. And, I spend more time ensuring that safety practices are followed, than the average individual in our department.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "Do you prefer doing work on a routine day-to-day basis or do you prefer mixing up your routine occasionally?", "answers": ["Are you the individual who prefers to know what the routine will be, or do you thrive on the challenge and excitement of unpredictability?", "\"I prefer working in a more predictable environment because I can be more effective in my tasks. With that said, I can certainly work in an unpredictable environment from time to time.\"", "\"I do prefer when the workplace is organized, and I am prepared for my daily tasks ahead of time. A solid level of organization creates efficiencies, and I can submit a complete job. I can also adapt well when unexpected situations arise.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "How do you show your co-workers the importance of communication in the workplace?", "answers": ["In the logistics industry, clear communication is incredibly important. Talk to the interviewer about how you put dialogue into action in the workplace.", "\"I show my co-workers the importance of communication through my willingness to ask questions if I do not understand the first time. I do not pretend to know something to save face. By creating an environment where questions are encouraged, we increase communication greatly, and see a healthier safety record as a result.\"", "\"I show my co-workers the importance of communication in the workplace simply from leading by example.  I set the tone and expectations for how we should communicate by utilizing all forms of written, verbal and interpersonal communications, early and often in the process.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "At Company ABC we hire a diverse workforce. When have you worked among a diverse group of people?", "answers": ["Are you accustomed to working with a very large or diverse team of individuals? Assure the interviewer that you can handle an environment that offers diversity. Discuss how your personality lends to being comfortable with a variety of people and situations.", "\"I have worked with diverse groups of people most of my career, including my time in University. I am most comfortable, and happy, in this type of environment because it offers a great learning opportunity.\"", "\"I would say that pretty much every company I have worked for has valued diversity.  Working with people from all walks of life help shed different perspectives and identify potential problems faster.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "How do you manage a large workload?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you can handle the workload required of you in this position with Company ABC. Start by clarifying that you never let a large workload stress you out. Let the interviewer know that you complete each task by priority level and, before you know it, your large workload is complete.", "\"When I have a large workload on my plate, I do not stress over the tasks that are in front of me. Rather, I make a simple plan of which tasks are a high priority and which tasks are a lower priority. The higher priority tasks, I complete first. Through this system, I can focus on my tasks individually, rather than stress out by the multitude of tasks ahead of me.\"", "\"My workload is always packed, but consistent. The only time it gets hectic is if we've had a lot of assessments and I've gotten behind in grading. My work schedule leaves no room for error; I have a class starting at the same time the previous one ends. So, I am accustomed to having an incredibly full workload.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "How do you handle stress?", "answers": ["Are you someone who can handle stress on the job? How do you manage the stressful times? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to control pressure in the workplace.", "\"I handle stress very well, and when you call my references, they will attest to this fact. When I am under pressure on the job, I focus on the task at hand and make sure not to get distracted. Staying on deadline is very helpful, and I will delegate when necessary to alleviate some stress.\"", "\"Stress is part of any demanding job, and I embrace it to the fullest. I take good care of myself and prioritize my workload to maintain a healthy balance in my stress levels.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "How can we motivate you on the job?", "answers": ["Every employer should know how each staff member is best motivated. Talk to the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you receive motivation on the job.", "\"I am best motivated through words of praise and recognition for a job well done. I do like to know that my efforts are noticed. In my current position, we have a leaderboard, and I do like that concept because it creates a healthy bit of personal competition for me as well.\"", "\"It's important to me that I felt capable and trusted in the workplace. If you see me doing a great job, let me know. Also, you could offer me additional, and more senior, responsibilities.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "What types of activities keep you busy, outside of work?", "answers": ["Having hobbies and interests outside of work is a vital part of maintaining a healthy work/life balance. Talk to the interviewer about the activities that interest you outside of the workplace.", "\"I have a variety of hobbies that keep me busy outside of work hours. First, I have two children who are involved in basketball and gymnastics. I also play in a baseball beer league, I volunteer at our community church and like to read.\"", "\"I am a very physically active person, with a passion for outdoor sports. I love to ski, snowboard, and skate. I play in an adult hockey beer league, as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "What is your definition of hard work?", "answers": ["Hard work and dedication can be interpreted differently by everyone. To one person, another person's hard work could seem like slacking. Talk to the interviewer about how you interpret a hard day's work.", "\"For me, hard work means that I did what I could that day to exceed expectations. I come to work early and stay late if needed and I go over and above the requirements without hesitation.\"", "\"To me, hard work means going over and above the call of duty whenever the opportunity arises. It means giving my best to my employer every day.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "Company ABC tries to be competitive in the marketplace but some roles do not pay as well as our competitors. Is compensation the most important factor for you when taking a new job?", "answers": ["In addition to compensation, there are many other factors to a fulfilling career. Talk to the interviewer about other factors that are important to you when considering a new job.", "\"Salary is important to me because I know that I am skilled and well educated. With that said, I do look at the full picture which includes factors such as benefits, work-life balance, perks, and company culture.\"", "\"Several factors are important to me when taking a job. Compensation is a driving component of that along with company mission, culture, benefits, and location.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Logistics", "question": "What causes you to feel dissatisfied on the job?", "answers": ["Everyone will have their particular triggers that cause them to feel dissatisfaction on the job. Talk to the interviewer about any factors that may deflate or discourage you in the workplace.", "\"I can feel dissatisfaction on the job when I am not feeling heard or when there is not mutual respect among the team members. I work best in more harmonious situations where there is little drama or gossip.\"", "\"I have felt dissatisfied on the job when I feel underpaid and overworked. I don't mind working hard at all, but I don't like to feel as though I'm being taken advantage of.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Company ABC values team synergy. Tell me about the type of people you enjoy working with.", "answers": ["Company culture and team harmony are essential topics for Company ABC. First, because these factors directly impact employee retention. Second, because happy environments are proven to be safer, overall. \n\nTalk to the interviewer about the types of colleagues that you most appreciate working alongside. Keep your answer positive and avoid speaking poorly of someone from the past. \n\nTraits you might like to see in your colleagues could include positive, encouraging, reliable, conversational, collaborative, or passionate.", "\"I enjoy working with individuals who work hard and love what they do. Being surrounded by those who value safety makes me feel great. Also, I appreciate those who are reliable and show up when and where expected.\"", "\"I work best with people who have a strong work ethic and value precision. Every delivery goes smoother when you have dedicated people on your team!\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Do you have any concerns around this role, or working for Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know ahead of time if there is any reason for you to decline a job offer, should you be the successful candidate. If you do have hesitations, be sure to frame them as positively as possible. Ask smart questions, and gain clarification anywhere you need. If you do not have any concerns, that's great! You should still have a question or two prepared for the end of your interview to show engagement and thoughtfulness. \n\nSome questions you can ask include: \n\n- What was the biggest struggle for the person in this role, previously? \n- If hired, what do you believe will be my biggest hurdle in the first 90 days? \n- What is the most significant change your industry has gone through this year?", "\"You mentioned a high rate of employee turnover. I have a great amount of experience working with companies that need an overhaul related to employee engagement but would like to know what situation I would be facing. Do you have numbers or stats to share?\"", "\"Thank you for asking! I do not have any concerns, but I do have a couple of questions. What do you foresee as the biggest challenge I will face, in my first 90 days of employment? I want to start strong and come prepared to meet these challenges.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Your background is not in rail transport. Tell me what skills and characteristics qualify you for this position, regardless of your lack of industry experience.", "answers": ["There are a variety of ways that you can be a good fit for a job; regardless of the industry from which you come. This question is your opportunity to discuss the transferable skills you bring to this position. Transferable skills can include safety training, mechanical abilities, customer service experience, and software capabilities, for instance. Be prepared to position yourself as the best candidate for the job, regardless of your direct industry experience.", "\"I come from a welding environment versus a rail transport setting; however, the importance of what I did in terms of accuracy and safety are the same that you ask for in your job posting. I put safety first, and I am highly technical and mechanically minded, no matter what the industry.\"", "\"It's tough to teach time management, troubleshooting, and safety skills; however, industry knowledge is something I can learn. I have begun to study the rail transport industry already and will have a firm grasp before my start date. If you have any suggestions on resources to gain further industry knowledge, I am happy to look into them.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "In this role with Company ABC you will be responsible for the safe and efficient operation of trains and the movement of customer freight from one destination to another. How will you contribute to our reputation for safety and excellence?", "answers": ["In the rail transport industry, nothing is more important than safety and pride in work. Take some time on Company ABC website to learn about their mission statement and values. Now, take a look at your values, work ethic, and top skills. How are they a match? Talk to the interviewer about how your skills and characteristics will contribute to the goals of Company ABC.", "\"I read that Company ABC abides by key principles which include Employee Development, Operational Safety, Diversity & Inclusion, and Customer Excellence. I too am committed to opportunities for development and growth. I seek out an exciting career that is safe and rewarding for all. I plan to contribute by abiding by your policies, leading by example, and being an encouraging team member to my colleagues.\"", "\"Serving customers safely is the theme that I have read on your website and a goal that I plan to help you achieve every day that I am on the job. Your trains pass through small towns, big cities, and everywhere in-between, which is why a firm commitment to safety is of utmost importance. I will invest time in learning your equipment and infrastructure, getting to know my colleagues, and learning about the customers that you serve. Through this dedication to knowledge, I can contribute to your history of safety and customer service excellence.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Which aspect of working within the rail transport industry is most exciting for you?", "answers": ["The rail transport industry is diverse, with many opportunities for travel, growth, and learning. This question helps the interviewer to see what type of research you have done on the role and the industry as a whole. Refer to the job description to see if any particular tasks or responsibilities are real stand-outs for you. Be sure to bring enthusiasm to your response!", "\"In the job posting, you mentioned seeking someone who can assist and instruct train crews to couple and uncouple cars, operate switches, and make minor repairs to railcars, including replacing heavy couplings or air brake hoses. I am looking forward to the opportunity to utilize my heavy mechanic's experience and equipment failure troubleshooting expertise.\"", "\"I get very excited about opportunities to problem solve and troubleshoot. For that reason, I believe the greatest aspect of working in the rail transport industry will be the opportunity to ensure smooth and effective movement of priority trains, trains containing hazardous material or restricted shipments. Every success related to smooth transport without delays will be very satisfying.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "How do you maintain familiarity with scheduled trains, destinations, times of arrivals, and departures?", "answers": ["Being able to remain on schedule, keeping track of arrivals and destinations, and all the moving parts in between will be a critical part of your role at Company ABC. Flawless execution means that you are familiar with your job, and well-briefed at the beginning of each shift. \n\nThe interviewer needs to see that you understand the urgency that comes with all of these responsibilities. If you already work within these parameters, be sure to share that fact with the interviewer. Talk about how you keep organized, ensuring a job well done.", "\"I maintain familiarity with scheduled trains, destinations, arrivals, and departures by fully briefing myself on my day before I even begin. Then, I revisit expectations regularly throughout the day. My current company also uses a robust data management system where I can see the movement of my trains in real time; allowing me to troubleshoot issues before they happen.\"", "\"I plan to maintain familiarity with scheduled trains, destinations, arrival times, and departures by fully utilizing the programs and systems put in place by Company ABC. I am tech savvy and know that by learning your systems very early on, I will be that much more effective in my job.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Do you have experience working on an on-call basis? Are you willing and able to comply with an on-call schedule?", "answers": ["Rail transport crews often need to work on-call, being available to work safely with just a couple of hours' notice at times. The interviewer needs to see that you can comply with the schedule, meeting the needs of Company ABC and filling the expectations of this role. \n\nIf you currently work on an on-call basis, let the interviewer know this. The best way to show your readiness is by explaining that you are already doing it! If you do not have experience being on-call, assure the interviewer that you understand the requirements of this schedule and that you can deliver what is expected of you.", "\"I currently work on-call, 14 days on and 14 days off. When on call, I often need to arrive at work in 2 hours or less. I completely understand the challenges that come with a schedule like this; however, it's what I am accustomed to in my career.\"", "\"My work schedule, thus far, has been primarily evenings and weekends. I understand that this role with Company ABC requires me to be on call quite often. I am willing to be a team player and work whichever hours are required of me.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "How familiar are you with the FRA (Federal Railroad Administration) and the part they play with Company ABC daily operations?", "answers": ["The Federal Railroad Administration (FRA) was conceptualized by the Department of Transportation Act of 1966. Essentially, the FRA's primary mission is to enable the safe, reliable, and efficient movement of people and goods by rail. \n\nIf you are hired by Company ABC you will need to be familiar with the FRA and how to comply with their regulations, as they relate to your specific job title. Briefly describe what you know the FRA to be, and how they will impact your daily work operations.", "\"The FRA is one of around 10 US-based agencies responsible for the regulation of freight and transportation by rail. I believe that as a (insert your job description) the FRA will have a significant impact on the safety practices of my job in areas such as hazardous materials, operating practices, and train control.\"", "\"The Federal Railroad Administration is actively involved in limiting safety risks in the rail transport industry; impacting, I believe, every aspect of my job as a (insert your job description). The FRA's focus includes hazard identification, and risk analysis, which greatly reduces rail accidents and the consequences of hazardous events should they occur.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Explain to me the responsibilities of a train dispatcher. In your opinion, what is the most critical component of a dispatch position?", "answers": ["If you are applying for the role of train dispatcher with Company ABC, it's essential that you have a clear understanding of your responsibilities and the expectations of this position.  You may think that this question does not apply to you if you're interviewing for a different role. However, it's vital that you have an understanding of this critical position, regardless of where you will be working in the organization.", "\"Train dispatchers have a diverse role which includes making sure that trains are arriving safely and efficiently. I believe that safety is the main priority for a train dispatcher as they communicate with the train drivers and conductors on every movement of the train. For these reasons, I think that a train dispatcher should have a keen eye for detail, be highly organized, and able to see potential issues before they happen.\"", "\"From the research I have done, I understand the responsibilities of the train dispatcher to be around team communication, compliance of every train and load, and to be on top of scheduled trains, destinations, times of arrivals and departures. This level of responsibility means that a train conductor should be able to coordinate multiple moving parts, be resistant to stress, and be able to be critically minded.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "This role with Company ABC requires union membership. How do you feel about being part of a unionized environment?", "answers": ["There are many bonuses' to being part of a unionized environment; however, there are some folks who do not wish to work in a unionized environment. It's essential that an employer checks for preference, so they can avoid any issues arising in the future. If this role with Company ABC requires you to be part of a union, be prepared to discuss your willingness to join the union. You can certainly ask questions about their collective agreement, or what the union has done to collaborate with Company ABC in the recent past.", "\"I have worked in a union environment for the past three years, and am willing to work in another union environment again. I appreciate the pay standards and workplace protections that come from being part of a union; two points that are very important when working in an industry like rail transport.\"", "\"Union environments are new to me; however, I am eager and open to learning more. If you could share with me a little bit about how active the union is at Company ABC and what they have done to benefit the lives of employees and the company culture, I would greatly appreciate the additional information.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Explain to me the role of a freight conductor. What do you feel are the top 3 skills a freight conductor at Company ABC should possess?", "answers": ["The hiring authority at Company ABC wants to know that you have a complete understanding of this role, your future responsibilities, and the expectations present should you be the successful candidate. Of course, you will only be asked this question if you are applying for a freight conductor role. \n\nIf you are interviewing for a different job title, you should still do some research on the fright conductor role considering it's always a great idea to have an understanding of other positions within your company.", "\"The primary purpose of a freight conductor is to oversee railroad movements, the safety of a train, and the movement of a train. Communicating with the rail traffic controllers, ensuring the train remains on schedule, supervising the train crew, and facilitating loading and unloading activities are significant parts of the job. Considering these tasks and duties, I believe that the three top skills a freight conductor should possess are time-management, problem-solving, and patience.\"", "\"From my understanding, a freight conductor will spend their day managing the movement and overall operation of a train. Responsibilities include making sure the train is on time, switches are smooth, and that loading or unloading activities happen safely and efficiently. If I were hiring a freight conductor, I would look for someone who stays cool under pressure, puts safety first, and can lead a team with authority.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Walk me through your experience supervising crews, and facilitating schedules or loading and unloading duties.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to gain an understanding of your leadership activities. You may have leadership roles on your resume. If you do, be sure to bring this experience to life for the interviewer by discussing how many people you have lead, what their job titles were, and the volume of work you needed to facilitate. \n\nIf you do not have experience with supervising crews or facilitating schedules, think of other times that you have jumped into a leadership role without being asked. Show that you are a natural leader and someone who can take control of a situation when it's appropriate, and when you see the need.", "\"I have four years' experience as a freight conductor, leading teams of up to sixteen people at one time; primarily train crew. I have a vast amount of experience communicating with dispatch, ensuring that all loads comply with federal regulations and that schedules are aligned.\"", "\"Being new to my career, the leadership experience that I have is informal and mainly during times when my supervisor is unavailable, or I need to help a new employee learn something new. I think that I am a natural leader because I quickly see where there is a need and where a potential issue could arise. I am proactive and have a keen eye for detail.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Do you have experience collaborating with dispatchers, yardmasters, engineers and other train crew?", "answers": ["Cross-functional communication is one of the keys to a successful day at Company ABC. The interviewer wants to know more about your experience collaborating with other departments and job functions such as dispatch, yard crew, locomotive engineers, and general train crew. \n\nIf you are new to the industry, or your career, with limited cross-functional experience, you can try focusing your response on any volunteer work, or experience from your post-secondary education.", "\"I have worked in rail transport for the past eight years, collaborating with a variety of job functions every day. On a regular day, I speak with dispatch, the train crew, and our engineers multiple times per day. I am a strong communicator, both verbally and written. One of my strengths is in my documentation and reporting skills.\"", "\"The bulk of my collaborative work comes from a couple of large group projects while obtaining my certificate in locomotive engineering. I also completed my internship at ABC Railroad, which allowed me to learn how engineers collaborate with other departments such as dispatch and crew. I look forward to furthering my exposure to cross-functional collaboration when I join Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "At Company ABC we do everything as a team. Have you ever had difficulty working in a team environment?", "answers": ["Company ABC and its employees rely on great teamwork and exceptional communication to make every day efficient and safe. Explain to the interviewer that you can work well within a team environment. If you have had challenges in the past, you can discuss these challenges; however, it's essential that you then mention the positive outcome.", "\"I have no difficulty in team-based environments. That is where I thrive, as a highly collaborative crew member. I can work well on my own as well, but I do prefer the variety and excitement that comes with teamwork.\"", "\"I have never encountered difficulty working in a team environment. I have been lucky enough to work with an amazing crew for the past year, and look forward to even greater collaborative experiences here at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Describe your overall experience working around and operating heavy equipment.", "answers": ["When you answer this question, avoid merely listing off the equipment that you have used. Make your answer more conversational by also discussing any training you have received, troubleshooting you have done, and any areas of expertise you may have. \n\nIf you have no experience working around or operating heavy equipment, that is okay! Company ABC is willing to train the right person. Be sure to express your eagerness to learn. You could offer to take some coursework or training before your hire date, which will strengthen your knowledge before you start your new job.", "\"I have a great deal of experience with equipment for railway work. Some of the heavy equipment I have operated or repaired include (list the equipment you have experience in). For the past three years, I have been the go-to crew member for troubleshooting many of our heavy equipment failures. I am comfortable with anything that has an engine, and if I don't know what to do, I will research until I have the answers.\"", "\"Heavy equipment is new to me; however, I am tech savvy, and confident in my ability to learn to troubleshoot the most common pieces of equipment used at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Working for Company ABC can be physically demanding. Are you able to lift 50-85 pounds, work in confined or enclosed spaces, and spend much of your day bending, kneeling, and climbing?", "answers": ["The answer to this question should be a simple yes or no. Working in the rail transport industry is a physically demanding role and Company ABC needs to have complete assurance that you can handle these demands, accident-free. Keep your response brief and confident. If you already work a job that is demanding on you, physically, be sure to share those details!", "\"I am physically fit and able to meet every requirement of this role. In my current job, I lift 80 pounds regularly. I crawl into small spaces and spend a lot of my day standing and walking. Rest assured, I can meet the physical requirements of this position.\"", "\"I read through the physical requirements of this role before applying to Company ABC. I can lift heavy objects and do not have restrictions as far as heights, or crawling into tight spaces.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Federal regulations require Company ABC to conduct a series of background checks as well as random testing for drugs and alcohol. Are you able to meet these requirements?", "answers": ["Of course, you are open and willing to undergo a series of background checks! Show the interviewer that you have nothing to hide and that you are fully eligible to work for Company ABC. Due to the sensitive nature of rail transport, you will need to be able to pass drug and alcohol tests, as well as a criminal background check. Keep your answer straightforward.", "\"I am willing to comply with any background checks required of me, including criminal, credit, drug, and alcohol. I brought a recent police check with me today if you would like to take a copy for my candidate file.\"", "\"I am ready to abide by any federal regulations and any other needs of Company ABC when it comes to checks on my criminal history or drug and alcohol use.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Do you have experience working with trains containing hazardous material or restricted shipments?", "answers": ["Company ABC transports hazardous materials regularly such as gasoline, chemicals, and flammable materials. The interviewer wants to understand better the experience that you bring when it comes to moving highly sensitive shipments. Discuss the breadth of your expertise by giving details such as what you have transferred and how often, being sure to highlight your success and safety record. \n\nIf you do not have experience working with shipments that are restricted or hazardous, be sure to express the fact that you are safety conscious and comfortable working in a potentially dangerous work environment.", "\"In my current role we move dangerous shipments regularly. Before joining the rail transport industry, I worked in road transportation where we moved trucks of gasoline and highly flammable goods. I am TDG (Transportation of Dangerous Goods) certified and have had zero accidents throughout my career.\"", "\"I recently obtained my TDG certification and am ready for further safety training when it comes to hazardous or restricted shipments.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Company ABC values problem-solving and troubleshooting skills. Tell me about a time you solved a significant issue in the workplace.", "answers": ["Problem-solving and troubleshooting are fundamental skills in the rail transport industry. The interviewer wants to see that you are capable of problem-solving and troubleshooting in a high-pressure or high-stakes environment. Discuss a time when you solved an issue at work that had the potential to become a significant problem. Talk about the steps that you took, being sure to discuss the positive outcome in the end.", "\"Recently, it was clear that our operational and field staff felt taken for granted and disregarded by the corporate office. Not only did they feel devalued due to budget cuts and layoffs, but morale was also low from some issues surrounding our union's collective agreements and recent changes. Rather than just let these feelings fester, I decided to listen to the ops staff and then bridge the gap with corporate and the union. By sitting down and having a conversation, and laying out a more effective way of delegating work, promoting those who worked hard, and helping our operational and field staff to feel more job security; everyone walked out feeling better about the job, situation, and their coworkers.\"", "\"I problem solve quite often at work, primarily with customer resolution. Just yesterday, I worked with a transport customer who was unhappy with a significant delay in their shipment. Through patient communication, I was able to resolve the complaint and create another returning customer.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "In the rail transport industry, reaction time is everything. How often do you create alternative scenarios to help you adjust to potential change?", "answers": ["Situations can change on a dime in the rail transport industry, and the interviewer needs to see that you have the insight to always have a 'Plan B' in your back pocket. Talk to the interviewer about your ability to create a variety of potential scenarios and solutions. You may never need to take on these scenarios; however, it's vital for the interviewer to know that you can adapt your plan on the fly.", "\"Any transport job can be unpredictable and requires a great amount of adaptability. Recently we had a huge recall of a hazardous product that we were transporting. Our customer was trying to stop the shipment; however, we were unable to turn the shipment around as we had other clients who needed their delivery on time. We made plans with the client for a shipment return, which changed my work schedule significantly; however, that's to be expected in this industry. I always plan for schedule changes.\"", "\"Nothing is guaranteed to go smoothly in the rail transport industry; that is one thing I know for sure. I always create 'what-ifs' because I know that plans change quickly, especially where there are multiple decision-makers and safety variables between myself and the delivery. Plan B is always ready to go.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Have you ever been terminated from a position?", "answers": ["For safety reasons and various legalities, Company ABC needs to perform stringent backchecks, which may include employment verification. The hiring authority needs to know that you are trustworthy and that you have not been fired in the past for reasons that will put their company at risk. \n\nBeing fired can be a stressful life event; however, it happens to many people every day, and often for situations that are out of our control. It's best to own up to it if you have ever lost your job. Be brief in your explanation but also let the interviewer know what you learned from the situation.", "\"I have never been asked to leave a role; however, I have worked in temporary labor positions that were not a good fit. I understand what it is like to feel the insecurity of unemployment and always commit to delivering my finest work. Rest assured, my job history is clean, and I have never been let go for insubordination. You are free to phone any of my references to discuss my work history further.\"", "\"I have never been terminated from a job because I deliver my best work every day. If my employer felt that I was not performing to expectations, I hope that a transparent conversation would take place so that I could redeem myself.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Successful communication between departments is key to success at Company ABC. How do you encourage healthy communication in the workplace?", "answers": ["The hiring authority at Company ABC would like to know that you lead by example when it comes to communication efforts on the job. Breakdown of communication in the rail transport industry can have dire effects on deliverables, reputation, and safety. These reasons are why clear communication is essential in your job.", "\"Many customer and delivery issues stem from poor communication. When we have a delivery issue in my current role, I work with my team to explore what happened, and how we can prevent it from happening again. We often role play and discuss ways that we could have reacted better. This practice has greatly improved our customer reviews.\"", "\"I show my co-workers the importance of communication through my willingness to ask questions or seek clarification. I do not pretend to have an answer just to look smart. By creating an environment where it's safe to ask questions or ask for clarification, our customer service has improved, we have more on-time deliveries, and fewer workplace accidents.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Stress is an every-day presence in the rail transport industry. How do you manage in the most stressful situations?", "answers": ["With high-stakes situations being an every-day occurrence at Company ABC, the hiring authority needs to know that you can keep your cool no matter what tasks come your way. Your ability to manage stress will directly impact your job performance. Think of some ways you have learned to deal with stress at work, and give a real-life example to the interviewer.", "\"I realize that the rail transport industry is high-stakes, so it's critical that I manage that stress like a pro. I tend to work best in stressful situations. For instance, the pressure of delivery deadlines drives me to work faster and smarter. I am resistant to stress because I choose to focus on the end goal rather than the small hiccups along the way.\"", "\"I do well under pressure or stress, but like most people, sometimes I need to take a minute to recalibrate under high-pressure situations that offer little relief. I know myself, and my stress triggers pretty well, so when I feel like there's too much on my plate, I will center myself, dig in and get through it, knowing I'll come out better on the other side.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Company ABC needs reliable team members who can adhere to our schedules. How many days were you unexpectedly absent from work last year?", "answers": ["Depending on the role for which you are interviewing, there may be expectations for you to be on call 24-7, or be available to come into work within just a couple of hours' notice. Company ABC may ask you to work double shifts, evenings, weekends, and holidays. Assure the interviewer that they can rely on you to show you to work when expected.", "\" My parents raised me with an old-fashioned mindset where you go to work unless it's an absolute emergency. The last sick day I took was about three years ago. I expect dedication from my teammates so that I don't have to cover for their shifts for fickle reasons. I deliver the same level of respect and reliability at the same time.\"", "\"I have had zero unexcused absences in the last two years. In total, I took eight vacation days out of my ten days holiday time. I always try to be 10 minutes early for my shift. When you call my references, they will attest to the fact that I am highly reliable.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "How honest are you, on a scale of 1-10?", "answers": ["The hiring authority would like to know that you are a sincere and honest person that Company ABC can trust to do the right thing - even when nobody is looking! Giving yourself a rating from 1-10 can be a bit tricky since everyone has room for improvement. Be reasonable and give yourself an honest rating while backing your response with an example of your ethics and honesty.", "\"I value honesty and integrity very much. For that reason, I would rate myself as a 9/10 since there is always room for improvement, but I certainly try my best. I have never faced a discrepancy at work, or faced reprimand for acting dishonestly.\"", "\"When it comes to ethical issues, I always choose to be honest and truthful. For that reason, I give myself full marks! I have never faced an issue at work that tempted me to be dishonest. Integrity is all we have, and I am loyal to my employer.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Talk to me about your most recent performance evaluation. What was one positive, and one area for improvement?", "answers": ["The hiring authority at Company ABC  is looking for specifics of your job performance, leaning on recent reviews from your latest job. This question is another way of asking 'What are your strengths and weaknesses?' If you did not have formal performance reviews in your most recent position; discuss the feedback that you consistently received from your supervisors or colleagues. \n\nYour positive highlight can be big or small! When you mention one area for improvement, avoid mentioning something that would make you ineligible for the position. For instance, if you are interviewing for an engineering role, you should not say that you are disorganized or have trouble remembering important details. Also, be sure to discuss that you are actively working to improve this weakness.", "\"During my last performance review, my manager was very satisfied with my analytical skills, and ability to see data in a way the most others do not. I have a unique capability when it comes to data analysis. One area for improvement was to speed up my work a little bit. I am cautious with my reports and know that as I gain further experience, I will work faster.\"", "\"Formal performance evaluations are not provided in my current role; however, I often get feedback on-the-fly. My manager often compliments me on my ability to work unsupervised, and without a ton of direction. One thing that I can work on is my speed when documenting. I am not the fastest typer; however, I found a practice site that I have been utilizing online.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Company ABC employees are always busy, with critical tasks. Talk to me about what hard work looks like, to you.", "answers": ["The hiring authority knows that 'hard work' can mean something completely different from one person to another. To one person, another person's hard work could seem like slacking. Talk to the interviewer about what hard work means to you. Be sure to express your ability to work hard and keep up with the pace at Company ABC.", "\"My mom would always say, 'the early bird gets the worm,' which I agree with, but I think hard work goes beyond that. Being a hard worker means that you are invested in the goals and targets of your company. You don't leave your job until it's done 100% right. You also don't just leave your job the moment you walk off the site. It's always with you; thinking of ways that you can improve your performance the following day.\"", "\"Hard work includes the mental effort that I am putting into my deliveries. Working hard means striving to be a leader, and an example, in everything I do. I want to comfortably contribute to safety, process, and overall culture in everything that I do.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Name for me some specific characteristics that make you a functional problem solver.", "answers": ["There are specific characteristics that an employer will look for, to see if you will be an effective problem-solver; even in high-pressure situations. A keen problem solver will: \n\n- Think systematically \n- Be open minded \n- Admit when they do not have an answer\n- Value research and exploration \n- Look for the core problem first \n- Understand how to reverse engineer an issue\n- Will learn from mistakes \n\nConsider any similar skills and qualities that you may possess. Maybe you are highly positive minded, seeing opportunity when others can only see the problem. Share your problem-solving strengths with the interviewer, using a recent example of this in motion, if you can.", "\"What makes me a great problem-solver is my ability to gather facts, first. I look at the problem from multiple angles, and I am not afraid to make a creative decision, based on the pros and cons present.\"", "\"Learning from others is the key to my great problem-solving abilities. I observe and draw from the experience and mistakes of others. I never hesitate  to ask for help or advice when I feel stuck on an issue.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Company ABC works hard to offer competitive wages and employee perks. Besides your pay, what is the most critical factor when considering a job offer?", "answers": ["It's time to think about what is most important to you when considering a job offer from Company ABC. Financial compensation aside, Company ABC wants to know what you value. \n\nPerhaps your answer focus' on health benefits, work-life balance, company culture, career growth ad development, or even continued education opportunities. Whatever your answer may be, you must give the interviewer a clear idea of your career goals and what you need to gain from your next employment opportunity.", "\"Aside from a fair wage, I put a value on generous health benefits. I have a family of four, and having support for unexpected medical expenses would be an incredible addition to my compensation package. Could you share with me a bit about the benefits package here at Company ABC?\"", "\"I value the opportunity for promotion and career growth. I am missing out on future opportunities in my current job because they rarely promote from within the organization. This reason is why I am eager to know how Company ABC helps build up its employees for promotion and growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Rail+Transport", "question": "Working in rail transport can be stressful due to high-stakes safety issues and a lot of moving parts. What advice would you give to a colleague who seems to be cracking under pressure?", "answers": ["It's one skill to be able to handle yourself professionally under stress, but it's another skill to be able to help your colleagues who are feeling pressure in the workplace. \n\nBegin by acknowledging that the rail transport industry can be stressful, but you can handle it. If you come from the same industry, talk about the fact that you are familiar with the recurring pressures in this industry. If you are new to the rail transport industry, then mention everyday stressors that you face in your current job. Lastly, share with the interviewer what you would say or do to help a coworker cope with stress.", "\"I completely understand the pressure that comes with managing high-stakes safety and delivery issues in the workplace. If a teammate were becoming visibly stressed, I would recommend that they take a minute to gather themselves. It is surprising how many people are stress-wired in the workplace without realizing all they need is a quick breather. Sometimes a change of pace can fix so many feelings of stress and overwhelm.\"", "\"If a colleague were showing signs of poor stress management, I would tell them that talking it out is very helpful. If there is an issue bothering you in the workplace, it's wise to bring it up to a manager right away rather than letting feelings fester. I come from a high stakes military environment, so I am confident that I will flawlessly transition these stress-management capabilities to the rail transport industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "Judging by your resume, you appear to be overqualified for this position. What would keep you here, if you were offered the position?", "answers": ["Sometimes, hiring an overqualified individual can mean that they will leave when a better opportunity arises. Talk to the interviewer about why this position would be satisfying for you, long-term.", "\"I do have more years' experience than what you have outlined in your job posting; however, there are aspects of this position that would be new and exciting for me as well. For example, I would enjoy the exposure to more sales related duties. Despite my level of experience, there would be much for me to learn here.\"", "\"I do not think that I am overqualified for this role. I do believe that I bring a lot to the table, but my last few roles were with smaller companies where everyone wore many hats and had time to handle more responsibility. I like the idea of focusing on one job for a change.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "What causes you to feel dissatisfied on the job?", "answers": ["Everyone will have their particular triggers that cause them to feel dissatisfaction on the job. Talk to the interviewer about any factors that may deflate or discourage you in the workplace.", "\"I can feel dissatisfaction on the job when I am not feeling heard or when there is not mutual respect among the team members. I work best in more harmonious situations where there is little drama or gossip.\"", "\"I have felt dissatisfied on the job when I feel underpaid and overworked. I don't mind working hard at all, but I don't like to feel as though I'm being taken advantage of.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "What are your strengths?", "answers": ["Which personal advantages make you excellent at your job? Strengths can be skills or qualities that help you overcome difficult circumstances or accomplish challenging tasks. \n\nIn a work context, your strengths will help you to complete your to-do list, understand client needs, and help you to apply what you have learned in your training. Talk to the interviewer about a couple of your strengths and why those will help you to be successful in this role.", "\"I think my strengths are in my perceptiveness and ability to be observant of the needs of others. These strengths are part of what makes me an excellent performer in a client facing role.\"", "\"My biggest strengths include the ability to catch on to new material quickly, as well as my ability to maintain a positive attitude despite any negative situation. These skills allow me to be a valuable employee in nearly all situations.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "At Company ABC our facility runs 24/7. What is your availability? Do you have a preferred shift?", "answers": ["If Company ABC runs a morning, afternoon, and evening shift then you should go into the interview being very clear on your preference and availability. \n\nThe last thing you would want to do is take a role that isn't a fit for your lifestyle. Keep your answer to the point. There is no need to over-explain your scheduling needs.", "\"My wife and I like to arrange our work schedules around our children's needs. For that reason, I am seeking an afternoon shift. This way I can continue to drive them to school in the morning.\"", "\"Although I do not have many restrictions in my schedule, I do need to be available for a prior commitment on Friday evenings. Other that than, I am happy to accommodate any shift, and overtime, as required by Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "I see that you have recently worked for one of our direct competitors. Do you have a non-compete agreement in place?", "answers": ["In competitive markets such as the transport industry, you may sometimes be asked to sign a non-compete or non-disclosure agreement. Be honest and open with the interviewer about any existing restrictions you may have when it comes to working for a competing organization.\n\nIf you have a non-compete agreement: \"I did sign a non-compete with my current company; however, it just asks that I do not purposefully poach any of my clients from the past three years. I am not restricted when it comes to accepting offers of employment from competing transport companies.\"", "\"I did sign a non-compete with my current company; however, it just asks that I do not purposefully poach any of my clients from the past three years. I am not restricted when it comes to accepting offers of employment from competing transport companies.\"", "If you do not have a non-compete agreement: \"I am happy to say that I do not have any restrictions to my employment.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "If you could start your career over again, what direction would you take?", "answers": ["A hiring manager will be able to tell a lot about your personality by learning about your other career interests. If you could do anything over, what would you do, and why?", "\"I certainly do not regret the direction I have taken my career; however, if I had to start over in a new direction completely I would likely pursue my Degree in Education and become a teacher. Both of my parents were teachers, and they seemed to have a very fulfilling career. I enjoy coaching and leading others so, any tasks in my current career that related to these skills, are very welcome.\"", "\"I waited before completing my college degree.  While my career has been rewarding, I still wish I had gone to college right after high school.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "When have you worked amongst a diverse group of people?", "answers": ["Are you accustomed to working with a very large or diverse team of individuals? Assure the interviewer that you can handle an environment that offers diversity.", "\"I have worked with diverse groups of people most of my career, including my time in University. I am most comfortable, and happy, in this type of environment because it offers a great learning opportunity.\"", "\"I would say that pretty much every company I have worked for has valued diversity.  Working with people from all walks of life help shed different perspectives and identify potential problems faster.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "How do you like to encourage ideas in others?", "answers": ["Encouragement to others is a great skill to possess. Talk to the interviewer about your ability to encourage creative ideas in your team members.", "\"I like to encourage other people to be creative in their thinking and present ideas to the company, no matter how off the wall they may seem. Some of our most successful employees are ones who are confident in their ability to bring forward their unique ideas. I encourage participation through an open door policy and strong praise for those who show initiative.\"", "Here are some ways that you can encourage ideas in others: \n\n- Get to know them and what they like to work on\n- Send an encouraging email letting them know you like their plan or ideas \n- Publicly praise their efforts\n- If they are doing a great job, offer them more related opportunities \n- If you are a leader, then tell them that you like their ideas\n- Say things like 'Well done' or 'Nice work' on a regular basis \n- Show that you believe in their quality of work before they even deliver it"]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "Have you ever helped to implement a significant company change, in one of your past roles?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you have the type of personality where you can take initiative. Show that you are happy being an engaged part of your company, and team. \n\nPerhaps a new company policy was coming into place, and you helped to execute some changes. Maybe a new employee benefit program was introduced, or a new software implemented. In your example, be specific about what you did, and the impact your actions had - whether short or long term.", "\"Last month our company introduced a new software program called XYZ. I was already familiar with the program because I had used it in a previous role. I offered to do an employee training on the program, and my boss agreed to it. I took a lunch hour to give my presentation and then offered myself as the subject matter expert, moving forward. The implementation went very well, and my boss was thankful for my help.\"", "\"In my current position, I helped to rearrange our scheduling to save the company money on overtime and temporary staffing. I was able to make significant changes which ended up saving our company nearly half a million dollars in the first year. It felt great to make such a huge impact.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "We like to hire well-rounded candidates at Company ABC. Walk me through your freight management experience.", "answers": ["The interviewer is interested in knowing more about your range of experience in freight management. Try to focus the bulk of your answer on the primary focus of business at Company ABC. Take a few minutes to walk the interviewer through your resume and highlight any individual industry related training you may be received.", "\"My overall experience includes both domestic and international freight, with a special focus on sea transportation. The last four years of my employment has focused primarily on international freight. I am well versed in Safety of Life at Sea (SOLAS) and have a full understanding of International Maritime Dangerous Goods Code (IMDG) compliance and national transportation regulations.\"", "\"I am new to the sea transportation industry; however, I have been studying SOLAS and IMDG in my spare time. I am ready to immerse myself in learning more about this industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "If someone asked you the top 3 benefits of sea based transportation and logistics, what would you tell them?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to see that you have a genuine interest in the business they conduct at Company ABC. Briefly discuss with the interviewer what you feel the benefits of sea transportation are.", "\"There are some great benefits to sea transportation, but I believe the biggest three benefits of working with an organization like Company ABC are that it's a great solution for transporting heavy and bulky goods. Also, sea transportation offers much more flexibility when it comes to the materials allowed to be transported. Thirdly, sea transport allows the greatest quantity of materials in a load, because of their large storage capacity.\"", "\"That's a great question! If I had to choose the top benefits of sea transportation, I would say that it's more economical for large shipments, it allows for a wider range of materials to be transported, and it offers fewer restrictions on the type of materials shipped.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "At Company ABC we connect businesses who need to ship their goods with businesses who require those goods. This means that relationships are everything to us. What is your customer service philosophy?", "answers": ["Because Company ABC puts so much effort into their reputation, the interviewer needs to be confident that your philosophy on customer service aligns well with theirs. Be sure to research the Company ABC website and take note of any keywords they use when it comes to their clients and services. Match your language with theirs.", "\"I noticed on your website that you value your clients by actively listening to their needs. You also survey them regularly while staying on top of industry trends so that you can provide them with innovative new services. To me, customer service goes beyond friendliness and efficiency. You need to understand your customer's business needs and have the ability to analyze their future needs so that you can respond appropriately to their business landscape changes.\"", "\"I realize that \"The customer is always right\" must be a popular answer; however, I feel that first and foremost, the customer needs to trust your product and services. So, for that reason, I would say that my customer service philosophy is all about building trust and transparency.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "We have many strong competitors at Company ABC. In your opinion, what sets us apart?", "answers": ["Before your interview with Company ABC it's a great idea to get to know who their competitors are, and what makes Company ABC stand out from the rest. \n\nResearch online through a Google news search, or on the company website. If Company ABC has a 'News' or 'About Us' section on their website you will likely find some information on recent awards, industry accolades, etc.", "\"While researching Company ABC and the local market I did see that there are a few competitors in our area. What stood out to me was the enthusiasm of your team when I first applied here, and also the fact that you recently won the coveted Transportation Leadership Award. In addition to all of this, I see that Company ABC puts an important focus on carbon footprint. All of this makes you stand out from your competitors.\"", "\"You value your people and have an awesome culture centered around achievement, growth, and accountability, and you are disrupting an industry that needs some shaking up and you have science that is allowing that disruption. Honestly, the energy in here is contagious, which only make me more excited about the opportunity.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "Why do you see Company ABC as a long term career fit? How does sea transportation fit into your long term career goals?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about the type of career growth that you would like to see with Company ABC. Why do you want a career in the sea transport industry, and how do you think this position will satisfy that desire?", "\"I love the logistics and critical thinking required of me in the sea transport industry. It is continually challenging. What excites me most about this opportunity is that there is room for advancement in a leadership role. I would like to work my way to a significant leadership position with Company ABC over the coming years.\"", "\"This position aligns nicely with my career goal of continued growth.  The role is in my comfort zone, but a new enough approach that will intrigue me, and the company size is adequate to support growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "Company ABC puts safety first in all situations. What would you do if you saw a co-worker performing unsafe work?", "answers": ["The interviewer is wondering how you would react in a potentially unsafe work situation. If Company ABC is putting a lot of effort and resources into employee safety, they need assurance that you will appreciate those efforts and help to uphold their high safety standards. Answer this hypothetical question by using a real-life example, if possible. Otherwise, give a hypothetical answer. Be sure to compliment them on their safety efforts.", "\"If I saw a co-worker performing hazardous work I would act according to Company ABC policy. If the individual reported to me, I would swiftly ask them to stop what they were doing and would re-train them on the correct behavior. I would be sure to document the situation as well. In my opinion, there is no room for safety shortcuts in the workplace, and I appreciate that Company ABC puts so much effort into safety efforts.\"", "\"I believe that Company ABC has strong policies in place for unsafe behavior in the workplace. If I were to see a co-worker performing unsafe work, I would follow the protocols in place for a situation like that.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "Have you ever worked in a unionized environment? How do you feel about unions?", "answers": ["You may love unions, or you may have adversity towards them. The best thing to do when you are asked a question like this is to give an answer that is positive, either way. \n\nLike there is always two sides to a story - there is still a positive to find from either side. Talk about your experience in a union environment; however, if it was not a positive one, it's highly recommended that you avoid complaining. Pick a positive note and focus on that.", "\"I feel that unions have their place in many situations. I worked in a unionized environment for three years with Company ABC, and the union created a smoother and more organized environment.\"", "\"Although I have not worked in a unionized environment in the past, I do see why a union environment would be helpful to many industries and workplaces. They create strong policy, standards, and expectations that protect all parties. Are you a unionized environment here at Company ABC?\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "This position may require you to lift up to 50 pounds, bend, and stand throughout the day. Are you able to meet the physical requirements for this role at Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants assurance that you can safely handle the physical requirements of the job. The best way to answer this is to talk about the physical demands of your current / most recent position. Alternately, you can discuss the ways you ensure you're in peak physical condition.", "\"Yes, I can meet these physical requirements. In my current position, I lift up to 65 pounds throughout the day. I have never had a physical injury in the workplace.\"", "\"I have a slight restriction with lifting because of a knee injury from my days playing soccer. I can lift up to 50 pounds, bend, and stand; however, I do wear a knee brace. Rest assured, I diligently practice safety in the workplace and would never take on a task beyond my physical capabilities.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "Give me an example of a time when you went above and beyond.", "answers": ["Display to the interviewer that you can do more than just the bare minimum. Show that you can react appropriately when you see that your employer has a need that goes beyond your usual day-to-day expectations.", "\"Last week I noticed that my manager had not completed the schedule for the following week. Some of the staff were complaining that they didn't have their work schedule yet. Rather than going to my manager with the complaint, I offered to take on some of her workload so that she would have the time to complete the schedule. We worked together for a couple of overtime hours that day and were able to catch her up on everything. It felt good to help.\"", "\"I often go above and beyond what is expected of me. Most recently, I agreed to cover for a co-worker who was on short-term medical leave. I worked 10 hour days for two weeks so that our work did not suffer any setbacks.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "Every day is different when you work at Company ABC. When have you had to shift your priorities in response to sudden changes?", "answers": ["Have you been asked to change your priorities on a dime? How do you react to this kind of shift in priorities? Assure the interviewer that you can respond professionally when it comes to sudden changes.", "\"In my current role, our schedule is changed on a regular basis and always at short notice. I have been able to adapt very well to these frequent, sudden changes.\"", "\"I had to shift my focus when I learned that we were acquiring a smaller competitor.  I had to change my plans to incorporate a new team, with new ideas, process, and procedures.  Instead of working solely toward increased productivity, I had to back up work toward bringing our new team up to speed and integrate them into our processes.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "At Company ABC we like to hire those who can think on their feet. When have you had to make a split second decision? How do you react under unexpected pressure?", "answers": ["Being able to make quick decisions and think fast on your feet sets top-notch professionals out from the crowd. We all make a lot of choices every day, so start off by telling the interviewer that you currently make a lot of quick decisions each day. Next, be prepared with a more significant example that will be sure to impress.", "\"My current position requires me to make tough decisions on a regular basis. I work well under pressure like that. With split-second decisions, I will always go with my initial instinct. Last week, I had to make an important transport decision based on unexpected weather. It worked out well because I am no stranger to multi-tasking and I have great support staff who are well trained and fast acting.\"", "\"In my current fast-paced role, this happens often! We handle a lot of customer situations and put them first and foremost. Often, we have guidelines we follow, and there are also times when situations call for creative solutions to meet customer needs. I make split-second decisions when resolving these matters in the best interest of the customer and the company.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "What are your weaknesses?", "answers": ["This question is a pervasive one, but it continues to throw people off. This is not the best time to talk about your communication challenges with your partner or how you need to work on your golf game. Instead, focus on your professional life. \n\nWhat is a quality that you are proactively working to improve? Whatever example you give, be sure that it is not a critical skill that will raise red flags to the employer. It's best to focus on a non-core skill when discussing your weaknesses.", "\"Although I am an Intermediate level user in Excel, I found that I was not up to date on some of the great functions offered by the program. I decided to enroll myself in an advanced Excel course. That course starts next week! I look forward to being an expert user soon.\"", "\"This is super cliche, but it's also true. I am not good at delegating to others. When I become submerged in a project, I don't like to give away any of the control. While this can be good, it can also definitely inhibit the outcome of the project and my growth as a team player and individual. \nI am currently working on this, as I know it is a deficit.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "What makes you the best candidate for this position?", "answers": ["Bragging about yourself in an interview can be tough to do, but this is your time to shine! Which characteristics and career accomplishments have made you a stand-out candidate? Perhaps you have received some academic awards or have been given special accolades in your most recent position. There is nobody like you, and now you need to express that to the interviewer.", "\"I am the best candidate for you because I have a consistent history of exceeding my targets and goals for the past three years. I have been promoted two times in the last year which is nearly unheard of in my current company. In addition to these successes, I have excellent cold calling skills which I will put to work immediately after being hired by your company.\"", "\"I am the best candidate because I have the right background, education, and experience.  I know that I can jump right in and get going with very little training time.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "Tell me about an achievement you are proud of. What did you find challenging about it?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you are capable of setting goals and reaching them. The person who aims to achieve more and more every day is the exact person that every manager wants to hire!\n\nDiscuss an example of when you overcame obstacles to reach a career related goal that seemed impossible. Or, share a time when you received an award, and talk about the most challenging parts of achieving that award. Highlight your determination and focus.", "\"My company has a President's Club for all top sales reps. When you reach PC level, you earn a trip to Mexico! Last year I told myself that I was going to reach the President's Club level, no matter what it took. I worked an average of 50 hours per week, I doubled my cold calling numbers, and utilized areas of our Sales Force program that most people in our company don't even know about. Mixing my strong determination with sound technical skills, and willingness to push through, I made it! I was proud of this achievement.\"", "\"After recently hiring an entirely new team of people to roll out a critical project, I realized they needed to learn to work together. I created a leadership training program and cross-functional work group sessions to bring this team closer at an accelerated pace.  It was a challenge to schedule and break the ice early, but we did it well.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "Would your former or current boss describe you as a worker who gladly goes the extra mile to complete their tasks?", "answers": ["You can say that you will go the extra mile, but it's best to give a real-life example to the interviewer about a time when you did just that. Offer up your references as well and discuss with the interviewer what you feel your most recent employer would say about you.", "\"My former boss would describe me as an employee who goes the extra mile. In my most recent position, I was always available by email, and many of my service clients had my cell phone number just in case of an after-hours emergency. When you call my reference he will be happy to expand on that for you, I am sure.\"", "Give examples of how you go the extra mile in the workplace. Here are some ways that employees will go the extra mile:\n\n- Starting on an upcoming project ahead of time, without being asked.\n- Taking action on any feedback, they receive from their manager. This action means taking a class to improve on a required skill or reaching a self-development book to help with communication skills at work. \n- Coming to meetings ready to brainstorm or, better yet, with ideas already jotted down\n- Creating new ways for themselves or their team to maximize efficiency\n- Going out of their way to make their customers happy"]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "How will you earn the trust of your coworkers?", "answers": ["Workplace relationships are essential to nurture. Talk to the interviewer about how you plan to earn the trust of your new co-workers, should you be offered the position.", "\"I feel that the best way to earn the trust of my co-workers is to be helpful, always do what I promise, and be honest with them at all times. Strong relationships have to be built on these principles.\"", "Here are some ways that you can build trust with your coworkers:\n\n- Show common courtesy. Say hello, hold the elevator door, bring coffees now and then\n- Be respectful in your communication, avoid over cc'ing unnecessarily in emails\n- Avoid being a distraction, and respect the use of their time\n- Respect their personal space and the line between work life and personal life\n- Always ask if they have time before diving into a conversation \n- Try to find the answer to your questions before running to ask a manager or co-worker\n- Connect with them on LinkedIn but avoid more person social media platforms \n- Treat everyone the same, regardless of their job title\n- Do not complain about your job to your coworkers\n- Reach out to new employees and make them feel comfortable\n- Own up to your mistakes and fix them\n- Be timely with your followups and meet your deadlines"]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "At Company ABC we believe in motivating our employees. How can we motivate you on the job?", "answers": ["Every employer should know how each staff member is best motivated. Talk to the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you are best motivated on the job.", "\"I am best motivated through words of praise and recognition for a job well done. I do like to know that my efforts are noticed. In my current position, we have a leaderboard, and I do like that concept because it creates a healthy bit of personal competition for me as well.\"", "Here are some ways that an employer may try to motivate you. Which ones resonate most with you? \n\n- Incentive programs where points are earned\n- Showing complete trust in your work and performance\n- Setting smaller, more achievable goals\n- Helping you to find your greater career purpose\n- Being a positive example to you \n- Maintaining an open and transparent workplace\n- Personalized incentives vs. Team driven incentives \n- Getting to know you on a personal level\n- Positive feedback based rewards system\n- Offering a healthy work/life balance by encouraging time off\n- Letting you know your voice matters\n- Allowing you to take the lead on projects that excite you \n- Handing out big-picture projects, so you feel that you are contributing to the company's future\n- Public recognition"]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "What do you think might be the greatest challenges faced in this job?  How will you overcome these challenges?", "answers": ["Even though it may seem like a dream job, the interviewer wants to know that you have realistic expectations of the role and that you will not be blindsided if problems or challenges present themselves. Keep your answer simple. It is okay to ask for clarification on the position if you do not fully understand what challenges are in store for you.", "\"I think the greatest challenges in this role will be to learn the proper operation of the equipment. Another challenge will be the physical aspect of the position as I will be required to stand and walk around most of the day. I will be sure to pay keen attention to training and ask questions along the way. In regards to the physical component - I will get used to the additional activity after just a couple of days, I'm sure.\"", "\"I would say the greatest challenges I'll face in this role is learning the industry ins and outs to be perceived as an expert when making the pitch to new clients. I'm not worried about learning the material or the pitch, but there's more to being credible than the company's pitch. I want to immerse myself in the industry jargon and attend as many seminars and conventions as possible. I've already begun subscribing and reading the leading industry publications so that I can get into the nitty-gritty of how it all works. Of course, I will also seek out mentorship opportunities where I can learn from folks who have been in the industry for years. I find they love to share their knowledge and it gives me a leg up.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "Would you rather be considered a personable leader or a dynamic leader?", "answers": ["This question can be a tough one because everyone wants to be liked and considered personable. However, being a dynamic leader can make you a proponent for change in the organization. A hiring manager is going to want to know that they are hiring a change agent for their organization vs. a friend for their employees.", "\"I do feel that I am a personable individual, but I won't always be everyone's cup of tea. I would much rather be a dynamic leader. As a dynamic leader I can ensure that the organization is benefiting from my presence and, at the same time, I can lead my team by example.\"", "\"I believe that being a dynamic leader can be subjective as not everyone will like someone's version of dynamic, especially if they do not like them on a personal level. For that reason, I would rather see myself as a personable leader. Being so, I feel that I could connect much better with my team and get to know them on a deeper level.\""]}, {"topic": "Sea+Transportation", "question": "What would you do if you were made aware of a co-worker being dishonest or stealing from the company?", "answers": ["Companies want to know they are hiring loyal employees. Make sure that you illustrate in your answer that you would do the right thing and represent the company for which you are working.", "\"Unfortunately, dishonest employees are everywhere, and I certainly would not consider myself a 'whistle-blower' in the workplace. If I found that a co-worker was stealing, or doing anything to harm the company, I would approach them directly to ask what was going on. There is a good chance of the situation being a simple misunderstanding. If it wasn't a misunderstanding and the co-worker was outright defiant with their damaging actions, then I would bring it, professionally, to the appropriate parties.\"", "\"I am sure that you have an internal policy for employee theft so I can assure you that I would follow the required steps to report the theft. I am a trustworthy person with a strong track record of honesty with my previous employers.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "What are your favorite, and least favorite, tasks in your current job?", "answers": ["You will want to deliver your answer positively, even when discussing what your least favorite tasks are in your current job. It's important to remember that the way you respond sets a vibe for your interview. \n\nWhen it comes to discussing your least favorite aspect of your job, you want to avoid complaining. Do so by describing it as a challenge that you are learning to face head-on. Take this question as an opportunity to shine when it comes to your ability to overcome challenges and dislikes. When discussing favorite aspects of your job, focus on elements that you will be doing in this new role with Company ABC.", "\"My least favorite aspect of my current job is my inability to work around changing regulations. At times, I can deliver the most exceptional customer service, but I find myself blocked by a rule or policy that I cannot control. To combat this, I continually research and stay ahead of changes in the trucking industry. This research helps me to see potential roadblocks before they become problems. My favorite aspect hands down are my customers. I love helping them get their shipments out on time and navigate the confusing world of cross-border delivery. \"", "\"My least favorite part of this position is sharing leadership responsibilities and duties with another assistant manager. I'm eager for the chance to take the lead on my own. That said, on the flip side, I have learned so much by sharing these duties. I have learned to work cooperatively and efficiently with others. This collaborative nature is my favorite thing about my work.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "Company ABC conducts background checks, drug, and alcohol testing. Are you able to meet these requirements?", "answers": ["The interviewer needs to know that you will be able to pass any background checks; including criminal, drugs, and sometimes even alcohol. Any business in the trucking industry has to be especially careful about safety, which includes avoiding any instances related to impaired driving. If you are applying for a driver role, you must have a clean criminal record, allowing you to cross borders without issue.  \n\nKeep your answer straightforward. If you know that you will pass any background checks with flying colors, state that you will comply with anything they need. If you may have a discrepancy, you should disclose this right away.", "\"I am happy to take any background checks required to work for Company ABC. I have a clean criminal background, good credit, and am free of all illegal drugs. I brought a recent police check with me today if you would like to take a copy for my candidate file.\"", "\"I am prepared to take any background testing required by Company ABC. My history complies with any federal regulations required to work in this industry. Rest assured, there will be no surprises during my background checks.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "Tell me about your post-secondary education and how it applies to the trucking industry. Are you interested in expanding your schooling, or gaining further certifications?", "answers": ["Company ABC wants to know if you have an interest in investing in your industry related knowledge. Depending on the position requirements, you may need to have a related post-secondary degree. If this is the case, take a couple of minutes to bring your education to life. Talk about the coursework that you took, and how it will benefit you in this role. Of course, we never stop learning! It's also vital that you show the interviewer your interest in continuing your education as your career progresses.", "\"I love to learn, and am always seeking out opportunities to strengthen my knowledge in the trucking industry. I enjoy both formal and informal learning opportunities. In addition to my Bachelor's Degree in Business with a major in Communications, I learn through reading, listening to podcasts, and taking online certifications through platforms such as Lynda. Most recently, I gained certification in Logistics and Supply Chain.\"", "\"I have a keen interest in continued education; formal or informal. This year I plan to attend seminars, conferences and take advantage of some online learning opportunities. As far as my existing education, I have a Bachelor of Science Degree in Transportation and Logistics Technology. My coursework included topics such as distribution channels, consumer and industrial sales, global trade, logistics technology, and transportation law.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "Talk to me about your geographical knowledge, rating yourself from 1-10.", "answers": ["Company ABC needs to know that you are confident in your knowledge of the areas to which they provide service. Working in the trucking industry, it's essential that you have strong geographical knowledge. This knowledge does not mean that you have to know everything about the US, Canada, and Mexico! It does mean that you have excellent recall skills and the ability to learn quickly. Company ABC may offer geographic testing, so be sure to offer your participation if that's the case.", "\"I would rate my geographical knowledge a 7.5 out of 10. There is room for me to learn more. Thankfully, I have a photogenic memory and can recall locations and facts very quickly once I have briefly studied the content.\"", "\"I consider myself advanced and a 9/10 when it comes to my knowledge of this region and our surrounding states. There are areas of the US, Canada, and Mexico that I am not familiar with; however, I am a quick study and will begin brushing up my skills right away.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "The trucking and transport industry can be stressful and high-stakes. How do you deal under extreme stress?", "answers": ["The trucking industry can be high-stakes, especially when you have time-sensitive deliveries or shipments that contain dangerous goods or hazardous materials. \n\nStressful scenarios happen every day at Company ABC and the hiring authority needs to know that you can keep your cool no matter the challenges you face. Think about a time when you dealt with an extremely stressful situation, and give this real-life example to the interviewer in the form of a brief story.", "\"The pressure of time and accuracy is incredibly high within the trucking industry. I spent three years working for a trucking and logistics company that specialized in the transportation of refrigerated pharmaceutical and biotechnology supplies. The pressure, knowing that each truck was potentially worth millions of time and temperature-sensitive items, was like nothing I have ever experienced. To keep my stress levels to a minimum, I focused on timing and made sure our team exercised excellent communication. When communication is clear, it's much harder for things to go awry.\"", "\"I deal quite well under extreme stress. Perhaps this is due to the years that I spent performing in highly competitive sports environments. Between the pressure to physically perform and the pressure to remain top of my class in university, I have developed a strong resistance to stress.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "Smooth communication is vital to the success of Company ABC. How do you ensure smooth workplace communication?", "answers": ["Company ABC needs to hire leaders who communicate smoothly every step of the way. The interviewer wants to see that you lead by example when it comes to communication efforts on the job, even when you are not in a formal leadership position. In the trucking industry, breakdown of communication can be incredibly costly when it comes to on-time deliverables, Company ABC reputation, and the safety of others. Discuss how you do your part to ensure smooth workplace communication.", "\"I ensure smooth workplace communication by asking questions or seeking clarification without hesitation. I do not pretend to have an answer to make a good impression. When it's safe to ask questions or ask for clarification, every aspect of a business can improve; including customer services, timeliness, deadlines, and even safety.\"", "\"I believe that most problems stem from miscommunication. I ensure smooth workplace communication by asking for clarification when I need it and double-checking that I understand the instructions given to me. Before I proceed with a task, I walk myself through the steps in my head, anticipate any potential hiccups, and prepare a 'plan B' just in case 'plan A' doesn't go as smoothly as I hoped.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "Company ABC seeks out the most honest employees. Have you ever kept the remainder of an expense allotted to you?", "answers": ["Honesty is a critical characteristic that Company ABC will look for in an employee, no matter their job function. The interviewer would like to know if you have ever falsified an expense report or kept funds not meant for you. Assure the interviewer that you will always be honest with your expense reports and any other aspect of your job that requires trust.", "\"I believe it would be unethical to keep any expense not allocated to me. I am keenly accurate with my expenses, records, receipts, and payments. If there is an overpayment, I will credit the expense report, and include the backup, on the next expense request.\"", "\"I have never been in a position where I had an expense account, but even so, I would never keep the remainder for myself since that would be theft. I take pride in my honesty and integrity.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "Company ABC seeks out employees who work hard, and show up for their team. What does having a strong work ethic mean to you?", "answers": ["Using similar wording to that of Company ABC, take the time to explain to the interviewer what it means to bring a strong work ethic to everything that you do. When you use specific buzzwords that Company ABC can relate to, you are showing the interviewer that you value the same ethics and that your work values align nicely. Try to avoid the typical 'I work hard and show up on time' answer and dig a bit deeper into what makes you determined and driven, accountable, and dependable.", "\"After reading through the Company ABC website, and your job description, I believe that you seek employees that understand their team relies on them. I am truthful, and I go the extra mile for my team. I look forward to coming to work every day and making a difference for your team and organization.\"", "\"I describe my work ethic as 'old-school,' where I am early for every shift, honest with people, interested in learning new skills, and I consistently show up when needed. You are welcome to speak to my references in regards to my work ethic, as they will confirm the same. I am proud of the great work that I deliver.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "Tell me about your least favorite personal trait, and what are you doing to improve yourself.", "answers": ["This question is another way of asking about your greatest weakness. If you had to pick one trait that you would tweak or change, what would it be? Mention one specific character trait and then focus on what you are doing to improve in this area. Avoid mentioning a habit so extreme that it would disqualify you for the position. Some common personality traits that people often work on improving include: \n\n- Being a 'know-it-all.'\n- Rudeness or arrogance\n- Dominating conversations\n- Moodiness or being temperamental", "\"I will bring a lot of positives to Company ABC but, of course, I have traits that I am always working to improve. In a recent performance review, my boss said that I am sometimes brief when giving instructions. I was training a temp and missed some steps because I assumed she already knew what to do. I am consciously trying to be more thorough in situations like that.\"", "\"I can turn to humor at inappropriate times. It's a quirk that I have been working on improving. This situation does not happen in a professional setting as much as it does in my personal life.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "In this role with Company ABC you will be responsible for the safe and efficient delivery of customer freight. How will you contribute to our reputation for safety and excellence?", "answers": ["In the trucking industry, nothing is more important than safety and pride in work. Before your interview, take some time to learn about the mission statement and values of Company ABC. Through their website and other internet searches, you will be able to get a sense of their values, as well as the type of workplace culture they are creating. Are their core values a match to your own? Talk to the interviewer about how your skills and characteristics will contribute to the goals of Company ABC.", "\"Safe and on-time delivery is the running theme that I found when researching Company ABC. I appreciate your never-ending commitment to safety and professionalism. I will invest time in learning your equipment and processes, learning how to best communicate with my supervisors and colleagues, and getting to know the customers and industries that you serve.\"", "\"I am committed to opportunities for development and growth, which is a core value at Company ABC. I am looking forward to carving out a career in the trucking industry built on safety and excellence. I will contribute to your company goals by abiding by your policies, leading by example, and being an encouraging team member to my colleagues.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "Talk to me about a serious conflict on your team. How did you help to resolve the conflict?", "answers": ["Conflict can be inevitable in the trucking industry as you face situations that change all the time, with a wide range of personalities and high-stakes projects. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you were successful working with people that worked differently from you. Walk the hiring authority through the situation, what you did, and what the resolution was. Be sure to highlight how you skillfully handled these conflict issues.", "\"My previous trucking company went through a merger last year, and the amount of tension amongst the team was quite extreme. People did not know if they were going to lose their jobs, o if their routes were going to be changed, hours cut, and more. Everyone was sharp with each other, but I chose to take the kindness route. I was a friendly face through it all and kept a positive outlook. I know that I did my part to alleviate a lot of the negativity.\"", "\"Two of my team members were in a feud over a process that they were both misinterpreting. Normally, I do not get involved in smaller conflicts, as I believe that most grown adults can iron things out without mediation. This event was different. I called a meeting between the three of us and let them know they were both incorrect. They were a bit embarrassed about the whole event and allowed me to re-train them in the process, the correct way.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "We offer competitive wages and a great compensation plan. What is most important to you, when considering a job offer?", "answers": ["Every person interprets the value in a compensation package differently than the next. For this reason, its essential that Company ABC understands what a tempting job offer would look like before giving you one. Take some time to think about what is important to you when considering a job offer. Perhaps it's excellent health benefits, work-life balance, company culture, career growth, or continued education opportunities. Whatever your answer be sure to provide the interviewer with a clear idea of what you need to gain from your next employment opportunity.", "\"I put the most value on growth opportunities. In my current role, there are rarely opportunities for promotion because we are a small, family-owned organization. I am eager to know how Company ABC helps build up its employees for promotion and growth.\"", "\"I am most interested in joining a company that pays fair wages and has generous health benefits. I have children, which means that support for unexpected medical expenses is important to me. Could you share with me a bit about the health benefits provided by Company ABC?\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "How extensive is the fleet at Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how much research you have performed on Company ABC before attending your interview. You can find the information that you need from a simple online search, or through the company website. Discuss what you have learned from your research. Show the interviewer that you are engaged and interested in what Company ABC is accomplishing.", "\"From my research, I understand that you are the country's third-largest full truckload organization. Your fleet is extensive with nearly 80,000 trucks and 20,000 employees. You offer premium logistics services throughout the US, Canada, and Mexico. I am eager to join your growing organization.\"", "\"Your fleet is the most extensive in the country. I researched your organization before coming here today and see that your fleet includes around 90,000 trailers and 30,000 employees. Because of your extensive fleet and talented teams, you can serve a wide range of customers in a broad array of industries, including automotive, agriculture, and retail.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "Carriers and shippers face many regulatory changes. How do you remain up to date on capacity, compliance, and safety standards?", "answers": ["There are many rules and regulations to follow in the trucking industry. The interviewer at Company ABC wants to be sure that you are familiar with the reputable and valuable resources available to you. Show the interviewer that you remain up to date when it comes to safety and compliance in the trucking industry. Refer to coursework that you take, company newsletters to which you subscribe, articles that you enjoy reading, or even Google news alerts related to your job function.", "\"I subscribe to alerts from the US Department of Transportation as well the FMCSA. I also like to listen to podcasts, and there are a few that are very helpful when it comes to our industry. These include the 'Under the Hood' show and 'Drivers' Talk Radio' podcast.\"", "\"I recently discovered that your company has a very in-depth and helpful quarterly market report as well as regular blog posts to which I now subscribe. When it comes to being up to date on safety standards, I follow the DOT very closely as well as other regulatory arms in transportation.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "How is our ever-changing economy impacting the trucking industry?", "answers": ["According to the American Trucking Association, we move 70% of goods by road. This statistic means that trucking is an incredibly important industry for the economy. This importance also means that our economic standing can significantly impact the health of the trucking industry. Show the interviewer that you have a finger on the pulse of what is happening in your industry.", "\"I notice the biggest difference in the trucking industry when we are in a tight economy. With a slow economy comes less demand for shipped goods considered luxuries such as cars and garments. Consumers spend less money, which translates to fewer goods shipped and fewer loads run.\"", "\"From what I know, a slow economy means that people are consuming less under nearly every category. This slow-down of consumption means there is less to ship out. For this reason, shippers will try to control costs by filling trucks with more than usual and then sending them out less frequently. I have seen shippers double up on a load, to save on costs.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "Name for me three of the transportation services offered at Company ABC.", "answers": ["The hiring authority at Company ABC wants to see that you have taken the time to get to know their business and exactly what they offer. Do your research on the company website and be prepared to talk about some of the services that stand out the most to you.", "\"I see that Company ABC offers a plethora of services ranging from intermodal and dedicated trucking to brokerage and cross-border freight services. My specialty is in cross-border services, which includes shipping to Mexico and Canada.\"", "\"I appreciate the range of services offered at Company ABC including your dedicated fleet services which are customized to optimize your clients' shipping needs. The other service that stood out to me includes your brokerage services. It's great that your clients are assigned a single point of contact for their business needs. The third service that stood out to me the most is intermodal freight shipping. Your offering is broad from transcontinental to express services.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "Do you have experience collaborating with drivers, dispatchers, and other crew?", "answers": ["Cross-functional or cross-departmental skills are essential when you're working in an industry like trucking because there are many moving parts to every project. Clear communication is key to a successful day, and that begins with ensuring you are on the same page as your co-workers, regardless of their job title or function. \n\nIf you have experience collaborating with other departments and job functions such as dispatch, loading and unloading crews, schedulers, or even human resources, discuss that experience. \n\nIf you are new to the trucking industry, or your career, with limited cross-functional experience, you can discuss any volunteer work or experience from your post-secondary education.", "\"For the past five years, I have worked in the trucking, transport, and logistics industry collaborating with a variety of people and departments. On any given day, I speak with dispatch, warehouse crew, clients, and schedulers. I am solid with documentation, which helps our teams' communication run smoothly.\"", "\"The bulk of my cross-departmental work comes from a couple of large group projects while obtaining my associate's degree in transportation and infrastructure. I completed my internship at ABC Trucking, which allowed me to learn how drivers collaborate with other departments, such as dispatch and crew. I look forward to furthering my exposure to cross-functional collaboration when I join Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "How familiar are you with the US Department of Transportation and the part they play with Company ABC daily operations?", "answers": ["The US Department of Transportation (USDOT or just DOT) was established in 1966. DOT focus' on regulating all types of transportation, including trucking, rail transport, aviation, public transit, and more. Their primary mission is to enable the safe, reliable, and efficient movement of people and goods by all types of transportation. \n\nIf hired by Company ABC you will need to be familiar with the US Department of Transportation and how to comply with their regulations, as they relate to your specific job title. Briefly describe what you know the DOT to be, and how they will impact your daily work operations.", "\"The US Department of Transportation works to limit safety risks in a variety of transport industries. I believe their work impacts every aspect of my job as a (insert your job description). The DOT's focus includes hazard identification, and risk analysis, which greatly reduces accidents and the consequences of hazardous events should they occur.\"", "\"The DOT is responsible for the regulation of transport through a variety of applications, including trucking. I believe that as a (insert your job description) the DOT will have a significant impact on the safety practices of my job in areas such as hazardous materials, operating practices, and control of all driver certifications.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "Do you have experience working on an on-call basis? Are you able to meet our scheduling needs?", "answers": ["If you currently hold a job that requires you to work on-call, then this question should be simple to address. You can display your willingness by discussing what you already do in your current role.\n\nIf you do not have experience being on-call, be sure that you fully understand what this entails, before you agree to meet the scheduling needs of Company ABC. You want to be sure that expectations are very clear from the start. Overall, the interviewer needs to see that you can comply with the schedule, meeting the needs of Company ABC and filling the expectations of this role.", "\"At the moment, my work schedule is primarily evenings and weekends. I understand that this role with Company ABC requires me to be on call for half of the month. I am willing to be a team player and work whichever hours you require. Do you have a sample schedule that you could share with me?\"", "\"I brought a sample schedule with me today to show you the hours that I currently work. At the moment, I work ten days on and ten days off. Although being on-call is what I am accustomed to, I would like to understand better the needs at Company ABC before committing to an on-call schedule.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "Do you have experience in the movement of hazardous material, restricted, or time-sensitive shipments?", "answers": ["Company ABC offers an extensive menu of services to clients, including the transportation of hazardous materials, dangerous goods, and time-sensitive deliveries. These jobs could include the shipping of gasoline, chemicals, and flammable materials. \n\nOutline your experience when it comes to moving sensitive shipments. Show your level of comfort and expertise by discussing what you have transferred and how often. Be sure to highlight your record of safety!", "\"I have moved dangerous shipments regularly for the past eight years. This transportation experience includes trucks of gasoline and highly flammable goods. I am TDG (Transportation of Dangerous Goods) certified and have had zero accidents throughout my career.\"", "\"I earned my TDG certification this past month and am ready for further training on hazardous, restricted, and time-sensitive shipments. I trust that Company ABC has the best training in the industry and I look forward to learning more.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "Trucking and transport require the ability to react quickly and professionally. How do you keep your cool in the face of change?", "answers": ["No two days are the same in the trucking and transport industry! The interviewer needs to see that you have the insight and capability required to pivot on projects when required. \n\nShow the interviewer your ability to remain calm and collected in the face of last-minute changes. Perhaps you create a variety of potential scenarios and solutions ahead of time. Maybe you read a lot on troubleshooting, making you a confident problem-solver. Whichever way you approach changing situations, show the interviewer that you are flexible and adaptable.", "\"In trucking, transport, and logistics, no situation is guaranteed to be successful. Even a very smooth trip can have a sudden roadblock where the team has to collaborate to shift and pivot. I always create alternate scenarios and plans because I know that situations change without warning. In these situations, I give recommendations and lead the team with authority. I take suggestions, and we work through a solution together, one step at a time.\"", "\"Trucking requires a great amount of adaptability every day. Just last week we had a job that required the transport of dangerous goods. Our customer attempted to change the deadline partway through the run. We were unable to pivot since we carefully planned our route for roads that accepted dangerous goods transport. We explained the situation to the client and pushed the project as much as we could while keeping safety first. It can be a challenge to find a happy medium between great client service and maintaining safety and good sense. I expect these situations in the trucking industry, so I am always prepared to go with the flow and make changes to my day.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "What is the FMCSA and its primary purpose?", "answers": ["The FMCSA is short for The Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration. The FMCSA is an agency within the United States Department of Transportation. The primary purpose of the FMCSA is to regulate the trucking industry. This regulating includes reducing crashes, injuries, and fatalities involving large trucks and buses. Talk to the interviewer about what you know about the FMCSA and any experience you have with the administration.", "\"I have worked in the transportation industry for the past twelve years, and I am very familiar with the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration. FMCSA plays a critical role in road safety. I know that the FMCSA came to be in early 2000. Since its introduction, the administration has made a very positive difference in the lives of drivers, carriers, and the public in general.\"", "\"A separate administration within the US Department of Transportation, the FMCSA is short for the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration. This administration, introduced in 2000, maintains a focus on reducing fatalities, injuries, and incidents involving large trucks.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "Are you prepared for substantial amounts of travel?", "answers": ["Depending on the role you are applying for, there may be travel required in this position. Be honest in your answer, discussing any roadblocks you may encounter when it comes to traveling for work. If you are unable to travel on particular days, for instance, be specific about those restrictions.", "\"As a trucking professional, overnight travel is nothing new to me. I currently travel for about fifteen nights per month. Do you have a travel schedule set for this role? I would love to have a full understanding of the expectations at Company ABC.\"", "\"Although I have not traveled overnight for work, I have put in a lot of miles on a 9 to 5 basis. I desire to be home with my family as much as possible but will also be a team player if overnight travel is required now and then.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "What were you doing during the gaps in employment that I see on your resume?", "answers": ["If you have gaps in your resume, be prepared to have a clear answer on what you were doing during those times. There is no need to go into extreme detail on what was keeping you busy. The main point of this question is for the interviewer to see if you are the go-getter type who sticks with their job loyally rather than someone who quits and moves on the moment things become hard.", "\"The gap in employment that you see from 2017-2018 was my parental leave. I had another three-month absence while caring for an ailing family member. I enjoy working, so any break in employment has been due to circumstances out of my control.\"", "\"Much of my employment history includes temporary or seasonal work. This type of work has allowed me to experience a variety of roles within many companies; however, I am now ready to sew seeds in a full time, permanent opportunity.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "When have you discovered a problem at work, and went above and beyond to repair the issue?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to see that you are the type of person to take a situation and repair it, rather than leaving it for the next person. Show Company ABC that you can add genuine value to their company by going above and beyond the minimum expectations. Your example could include a time you worked long hours and made sacrifices to overcome a challenging problem. Discuss the positive impact and the significance of your solution.", "\"When I was working dispatch, I noticed that there were some systems that were out of date. So, rather than involving my supervisor, I took it upon myself to complete the updates which required some technical know-how. It took about seven days of staying late for work, but it was worth the hard work when I saw the improvement in accuracy, moving forward.\"", "\"During our busiest delivery season, I noticed that one of our primary spreadsheets was not formulated properly. I am not an expert with Excel; however, with everyone being in peak stress mode - I decided it was something I could learn on my own. I watched a few online tutorials and ended up resolving the issue without the need to involve the rest of the team.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "What timeline do you feel is appropriate when responding to customers and other stakeholders?", "answers": ["Company ABC is all about delivering exceptional service. The interviewer would like to know what you interpret as a fast turnaround when it comes to responding to your customers. You should take note of how quickly your messages are returned, by this organization, if you are a past customer. You can even refer to your experience as a candidate!", "\"Trucking, transportation, logistics, and shipping are all incredibly fast-moving. For that reason, my clients are never left waiting for a response for more than an hour. What is your expected timeline here at Company ABC?\"", "\"My customers often need speedy responses. Between myself and my team lead, we ensure that all inquiries are responded to before we wrap up for the day. We return most customer inquiries within 3 hours. Could you share with me the expectations set by Company ABC\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "Tell me why you are leaving your current job.", "answers": ["This question is straightforward, but it tends to trip up a lot of job seekers. Have a rehearsed and honest statement prepared for every position on your resume. 'The role was no longer a fit' is an answer that will not go over well with most interviewers. Neither is a vague reply like, 'There was no room to grow.'  Give a specific reason without being negative or speaking poorly of the company, your management, or co-workers.", "\"My most recent position ended due to the company being in financial trouble. I was laid off with ample notice, which was positive. I have been traveling and have put out a few applications; although I am very selective where I end up next. I want to ensure that the next company I join is financially stable.\"", "\"I am typically not a job hopper, so it was a very challenging decision to leave my role after just a few months. The owner of the private transportation company was a very nice person; however, the way the company operated was not for me. I would get phone calls from upset clients at all hours, which did not allow for a healthy balance. I have picked up some seasonal dispatch work in the meantime to supplement my income.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "How would you handle a client who is exceptionally rude to you?", "answers": ["Company ABC prides themselves on excellent service and a positive approach. When you work in customer service, you will often come across rude individuals, so you must know how to handle these instances with poise and professionalism. Give an example of a time that you had to deal with a challenging customer. Be sure to include information on what you did to ensure a positive outcome! \n\nSome ways that you can efficiently handle a rude customer:\n\n- Remain kind, polite, and pleasant\n- Actively listen to their grievances \n- Apologize for the situation \n- Maintain a neutral tone of voice\n- Avoid taking anything they say, personally", "\"I consider myself pretty resilient when it comes to rude customers. This resilience helps me to deliver kind and polite service regardless of the attitude the other person chooses to have with me. If a client were rude to me, I would still treat them like every other customer. I would actively listen to their grievances and use my problem-solving methods to resolve the issue.\"", "\"I have a good amount of customer service and dispute resolution training. Because I take such close care of my customers, they are not often upset. When a situation like this does occur, I remain neutral, actively listen, and avoid interrupting in any way. I will then repeat what I heard by saying, 'If I understand correctly, what is upsetting you most is A, B, and C.' Using this approach, they feel heard which is all most people want.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "How would you deal with a supervisor who is a poor communicator?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know how you handle poor communication between yourself and a superior. Since you cannot often change someone's communication style, discuss what you do to adapt. Talk about a specific time when you improved communication between yourself and a supervisor. Outline your approach and the resolution.", "\"I recently worked for someone who was very brief and did not provide much direction. It is challenging to deliver on expectations when the goal and even the approach are not clear. This role did teach me independent thought and the ability to research and find answers for myself. As challenging as this situation was, it did give me a lot of skills when it comes to working independently.\"", "\"I worked in a busy logistics environment where major problems could arise from poor communication. Our team seemed to be all over the place at times, and our manager wasn't very experienced. I recommended that we have a team huddle every morning and in the middle of our shift, just for 5 minutes, to ensure we were all on the same page. This solution helped us a great deal.\""]}, {"topic": "Trucking", "question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answers": ["This question is a simple one that is very challenging to answer because it's not specific and open-ended. It can be challenging to know where to begin, and end! Many job seekers get tripped up on this question and give too much personal information, or go on a tangent for....forever. \n\nKeep your reply light, and relevant to your work and this job. Share how you became interested in the trucking industry, for instance, and what you enjoy about it. This question offers an excellent opportunity to describe yourself by discussing the strengths and qualities that you bring.", "\"I am a very active individual and love to go hiking in the mountains on my days off. I enjoy reading leadership books and continually educate myself on topics that make me better at my job. I have a high amount of energy to offer and am a skilled team player.\"", "\"I recently graduated with my Associate's Degree in Transportation and am eager to start my career on the right foot. I am passionate about the trucking industry and, in my spare time, even listen to transportation and trucking-related podcasts. I am an avid reader as well; primarily science fiction.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "We have had concerns with employee theft recently.  What would you do if you caught an employee stealing?", "answers": ["Some businesses have trouble with employee theft, and they need to make sure that they are hiring someone who is honest and trustworthy. Talk to the interviewer about the steps you would take if you caught a co-worker stealing.", "\"When I work for an organization, I tend to take pride in the work we are doing.  With a focus on delivering value to a company wherever possible, I would feel obligated to report a co-worker stealing from the company.  I will refer to any policy or guidelines available and speak to the manager in charge of the department where theft is taking place.\"", "\"I would most likely confront the employee first.  Sometimes perception can be wrong, and I would not want to accuse someone of theft falsely.  Upon confrontation, if my suspicions are validated, I would then alert my supervisor.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "How do you evaluate success among your team members?", "answers": ["When you are leading a team, it is imperative to be aware of the level of success that each team member is experiencing. One under-performing team player can drag down the entire group. Talk to the interviewer about how you can stay aware of each team members' success.", "\"I have a very in-depth and successful system for evaluating success among my team members. I check in twice per week with each member of my team. On Mondays - to set our goals together. Then, on Fridays, to discuss any successes and challenges. I have them self-evaluate, and then we create a plan for success for the upcoming week. I evaluate their success based on their follow through and willingness to work hard to reach their goals.\"", "\"I typically have KPI (key performance indicators) in place to measure the success of each of the members of the team.  I also manage our overall success in working together. For example, are we hitting on key initiatives within the department, developing each other for succession planning and having fun along the way!\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "Would you consider yourself a creative person?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about any interest that you have in creativity and how you have implemented that desire in the workplace. Even if you do not consider yourself to be a 'creative person,' there is a significant change that you have made creative minded decisions in your career.", "\"I do consider myself to be a creative individual. One example of this would be the telephone sales scripts that I crafted for our inside sales team. They were lively and effective, and sales increased by 23% in the first 90 days of implementation.\"", "\"I am someone who alternates back and forth with the right/left brain, but I will always consider myself a very creative person.  I admire the creativity and unconventional thinking in business and arts.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "Tell me about a contribution you made to the last team you worked on.", "answers": ["It is essential to show the interviewer that you are a team player. Talk about a time that you were recently expected to achieve a goal in a team setting. How did you go above and beyond to ensure that your contribution was felt?", "\"Last month our company asked upper management to complete a full inventory audit. There were 4 of us in total and so we broke the audit requirements into shifts. These shifts had to take place when the warehouse was closed. In the end, there was one additional shift that nobody wanted to take. I volunteered myself to do that shift to show my dedication to my job and my co-workers. The gesture was appreciated, and the audit was completed on time.\"", "\"My most notable contribution was my ability to analyze and predict market trends, and then create a successful marketing strategy.  Before me, there was no one with a true marketing background on the team.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "How familiar are you with NAFTA (North American Free Trade Agreement)?", "answers": ["As a wholesaler and distributor, one must be familiar with NAFTA and the rules surrounding the agreement. Talk to the interviewer about your familiarity with the agreement. Avoid giving a personal opinion on the NAFTA agreement.", "\"I have worked with NAFTA for the past 12 years and am very familiar with the regulations and processes. In my current position I am the NAFTA subject matter expert, often helping my colleagues navigate the regulations.\"", "\"I am new to the wholesale and distribution industry, so my knowledge of NAFTA is limited. I have conducted some research in preparation for this interview and will continue to broaden my knowledge base on this topic.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "At Company ABC we are always interested in finding new vendors and clients. Tell me about your experience in business development.", "answers": ["Opening your business to new clients and vendors is a vital part of your success in the wholesale and distribution industry. Talk to the interviewer about your abilities when it comes to networking and developing business.", "\"I am a strong business development professional and am always on the lookout for potential new vendors and clients. Currently, I spend much of my time cold calling on potential new connections. In my most recent position, I was able to expand our business' profitability by 24% by merely calling on former connections and asking for referrals.\"", "\"In my current position, I manage some of our company's largest accounts. What I do is a balance of account management and business development as there is always an up-selling piece to what I do. The past three years, I have grown my account base by 20-40%. In addition to this growth, I brought on an average of 8 new enterprise clients every year.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "How do you properly vet potential new vendors?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you can adequately discern between great and unreliable vendors. How do you ensure that you are only doing business with appropriately vetted vendors?", "\"If you do not properly vet your vendors you can fall victim to a bad product, short orders, and even fraud. Our company has a series of steps for all vendors to go through including company background checks and references.\"", "\"Every company has their processes in place before taking on new vendors. I plan to follow the processes of Company ABC to a tee.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "Wholesale and distribution requires strong negotiation skills. How would you rate your negotiation skills from 1-10?", "answers": ["Give yourself a rating when it comes to your negotiation skills and also back your answer with an example of a time that you negotiated a problematic deal.", "\"I am very experienced in the art of negotiation and would give myself a 9 out of 10. In this past year, I negotiated some solid deals including a steep vendor discount on one of our most popular wholesale products.\"", "\"I am a skilled and experienced negotiator. I cannot recall the last time I closed a deal that I was unhappy with. For that reason, I would rate myself as a ten, on negotiation skills.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "How do you feel that globalization has affected the wholesale and distribution industry in the USA?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on globalization and how it has affected the wholesale and distribution industry. Keep your answer factual rather than make guesses.", "\"Globalization has greatly helped our industry to become more profitable; however, in some ways, it has negatively affected the quality of the product. Now, more than ever, we have products that are made faster and cheaper - causing them to be more disposable to the consumer. It has caused us to have to be much more careful when it comes to the products we choose to import and distribute.\"", "\"Globalization is a two-sided coin. I feel that it has been great because it offers more options when it comes to manufacturers and materials sourcing. On the other hand, more guidelines need consideration when making decisions. Also, the quality of the product can more easily suffer.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "Describe for me a time when you made the wrong career decision. How did you correct your misstep?", "answers": ["Everyone has had a misstep in their career at one point or another. Perhaps you took a job with a company who was not as reputable as you initially believed. Maybe you took a role that was 'oversold' to you. Or, perhaps you declined an opportunity that you now regret passing on. The key to a great answer is to discuss what you did to correct the misstep.", "\"Last year, I was offered a management position that would have offered me the leadership experience I was seeking. Unfortunately, I turned down the offer for fear that I was not yet ready for the responsibility of being a leader to so many people. My lack of confidence in myself got in the way. I recognized that lack of confidence in myself and changed turned it around by attending three leadership workshops over the next year. Now I am bursting with confidence and am ready to take on this leadership role with your company.\"", "\"I once implemented a rewards program that failed. I had seen it work successfully in another organization with which I worked.  It was a learning opportunity for me that not all organizations are alike nor are people all motivated in the same manner. We learned quickly that it was not working and scratched it early, saving some company dollars.  In its place, we enlisted the team to create something that would drive them to perform and earn the rewards the team wanted.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "What career path interests you the most in this company?", "answers": ["This question is where it is essential to have completed some research on the interviewing company. Be sure to envision where you can see yourself fitting, and growing, with the organization before your interview. Do some research on what a career path could look like with this particular company.", "\"What interests me most about your company is that there are so many options when it comes to career growth. Ideally, I would like to earn my way into a Territory Sales role, then a Regional Manager position. Eventually, a Director of Sales or Marketing position would be ideal. Of course, I understand that this will take many years of dedication and hard work.\"", "\"I am interested in quality control. I am very analytical and love to solve problems. I understand that I have to learn the products before I can measure their quality.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "What questions do you have for me?", "answers": ["It's always a great idea to have questions ready for the interviewer. Review the company website and other online resources to ensure the questions you are asking are not mundane, or redundant. The last thing an interviewer wants to hear is a list of items you could have found the answers to from merely watching a video on their company site! \n\nHere are some sample questions: \n\n- When would you like to have this position filled? \n- How long has this role been vacant? \n- Is this a replacement search or a newly created role? \n- What is your favorite part about working here? \n- What is the company's primary goal for this position in the next 12 months? \n- Is there anything from my background and experience that I can clarify for you? \n- What do you see as the biggest change in this industry over the past 3 years? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"Thank you for asking - I do have a few questions. What is top of mind when it comes to filling this role? Also, what types of career growth opportunities would follow this position? And lastly, do you have internal candidates who are also interviewing for this position?\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "Market analysis is very important to us at Company ABC. What steps do you take to research the performance of a product before choosing to import it?", "answers": ["Market research is a skill that you must possess in order to be able to properly assess the best products to be bringing in for distribution and wholesale purposes. Talk to the interviewer about the way in which you research before committing.", "\"My methods of market research include performing social media polls and surveys. I also perform multiple focus groups every year. Rest assured, I will be bringing powerful market research skills to Company ABC, if hired.\"", "\"I am new to the distribution industry; however, I would say that the best way to research the performance of a product would be to test it in a small market before conducting a wide scale roll-out.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "When you suffer a setback, how does that emotionally affect you and your work?", "answers": ["Everyone handles the stress and disappointment of setbacks differently. Discuss with the interviewer how you typically cope with delays in the workplace.", "\"Experiencing a setback is always disappointing, and can be a bit disheartening, but I understand that it happens from time to time. If I experience a major setback, I will take a few moments to debrief with my manager and discuss what I could have done differently. Then, I move on!\"", "\"Setbacks can be trying, but I find that you have to learn how to lose before you learn how to win. While I never enjoy a setback, I use them as a stepping off point to something even better.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "When have you had to change a major component of your project due to new information being presented?", "answers": ["Being able to swivel the focus of your project is a necessary skill for your success in most careers. Talk to the interviewer about a time when a significant change occurred on a project. How did you handle the implementation of the new information?", "\"I had a large project last month that was nearly complete when the client called to say that the dimensions provided were incorrect. Because of this, our team had to re-do the entire proposal. It took us an additional four days of work but, in the end, the client was delighted with our work, and it resulted in new opportunities with them.\"", "\"All of our products are thoroughly tested after the design and prototype phase.  We were certain that the design would hold up to the endurance testing, based on the components used, but it did not.  We had to go back and adjust the entire product design to determine the cause and correct the fault.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "At Company ABC we always strive to provide the best products to our clients. How do you ensure a product is of high quality?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you can determine the high-quality products from the lower quality products. Talk to the interviewer about your abilities when it comes to product discernment.", "\"I am very good at discerning low-quality products from the best quality products. I listen to my customers and have been in this business long enough to have a beat on who the reputable vendors are. If a product receives consistently low reviews, I do not hesitate to pull it from my inventory.\"", "\"In my current position, we have many processes in place to determine the quality and to ensure that only the best products are distributed to our vendors. In addition to our quality control processes, we also spend a lot of time listening to our customers to find out what they like, and what they are not as pleased with. Putting out a high-quality product is very important to me.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "Do you have any training in sales or business negotiation?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about any additional training that you have received in sales and negotiation. Be sure to highlight your biggest take-away's from that training.", "\"I have a great deal of on-the-job training when it comes to sales, business, and negotiation techniques. In addition to this, I have formal sales training from Dale Carnegie as I took the 'Sales Effectiveness' course in 2015.\"", "\"I have on-the-job training in sales and business negotiation; however, no formal training. With that said, I am happy to take any related training that you feel would be helpful. Do you recommend any specific courses at this time?\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "Wholesale and distribution requires excellent organizational skills when it comes to purchase orders and inventory management. How would you rate your organizational skills from 1-10?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are capable of maintaining strong organization of your inventory and orders. Rate your organizational performance and support your rating by providing an example.", "\"I would rate my organizational skills as a 9 out of 10 because my previous manager has told me that my organization is exceptional. Because of my organization, I was able to reduce our back-orders by 63% last year alone.\"", "\"Organization is everything. When I am organized, I can ensure that deadlines are met, and resources are being used to their utmost efficiency. I would rate myself as a 10/10 because I greatly appreciate a well-organized warehouse.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "At Company ABC we prefer to hire candidates with a post-secondary education. Take a moment to walk me through your post-secondary education.", "answers": ["Take the interviewer briefly through your post-secondary education. You can highlight any of your best classes, top achievements, or recognition that you may have received while earning your degree.", "\"I completed my Bachelor of Arts degree with a major in Global Marketing in 2009. I am proud to say that I graduated top of my class!\"", "\"I value post-secondary education and appreciate the idea of continued education. I was unable to complete my degree, for financial reasons, but I do hope to return to online courses in the future. The courses that I did take were all related to business, finance, and organizational behavior.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "What has been your best performing product in the past 12 months? Why do you think it has done so well?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about the best product that you are responsible for distributing. In your opinion, why did it do so well? Keep your answer brief and be sure to avoid giving away any trade secrets or breaking any confidentiality agreements in place with your current employer.", "\"My best performing product this year has been (product XYZ). I knew that it would do well because we tested its performance in a small focus group before committing to its distribution. It has surpassed our expectations, which is great.\"", "\"I believe that best-performing products are the ones that are correctly branded and marketed. You need to do the initial research before committing too soon to a marketing strategy. My most successful product this year was (product name) because we spent more time working on the marketing and distribution strategy than usual.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "Many of our clients and vendors operate in other countries and time zones. Are you able to accommodate their needs by making yourself available outside of typical work hours?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are dedicated to your success with Company ABC and that you can accommodate a flexible schedule. Have you worked an irregular schedule before? If so - be sure to draw on that experience.", "\"There are no limitations to my availability. I can make myself available to work a variety of hours including evenings and weekends. If a deal is to be made - I can be relied on to be present.\"", "\"I am happy to address a clients' needs outside of regular work hours when it is an urgent need, or there is a deadline present. I would never leave a client hanging; however, a stable balance between work and personal life is also important to me.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "Many of our clients and vendors operate in other countries. Do you speak multiple languages? If not, how do you manage potential communication barriers?", "answers": ["Communication barriers can be present when you are working with vendors and clients across the globe. Assure the interviewer that you are capable of managing any communication barriers.", "\"If I have a client with a strong language barrier, I will often suggest that we communicate primarily through email as it's much easier to discern needs through written communication. I do speak English fluently as well as conversational Mandarin which had helped me as a wholesaler in the past.\"", "\"I do not speak any other language aside from English. With that said, when I work with clients in a different country and they do not speak English, I will utilize an online translation service such as Google translate.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "At Company ABC we are looking for sales professionals who can make an impact on our business immediately. How do you plan to do that?", "answers": ["Company ABC wants to be sure that they are hiring the best people in the business so that they can be a step ahead of their competitors at all times. Assure the interviewer that you are engaged in this process by discussing the ways you feel you could make an impact immediately after being hired.", "\"I plan to make an impact on the profitability of Company ABC through aggressive cold calling on potential clients. I also have some great ideas to bring in regards to vendor management.\"", "\"I come with an already strong portfolio of clients and plan to begin there. You have a great product at Company ABC so I am confident that the response will be solid. In addition to this, I plan to contact your past client list and reactivate some dormant accounts.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "How do you like to be recognized for your accomplishments?", "answers": ["We all like recognition in some way for our accomplishments in the workplace. Share with the interviewer how you would want credit for your hard work. Through gifts? Financial perks? Public recognition? Kind words? Title promotions?", "\"I am very much an over-achiever and find that the best way for me to be recognized for a job well done is through words of kindness and recognition. I am easily encouraged, and the best reward for me is to know that my hard work is noticed.\"", "\"I am very simple.  I do not really require any formal recognition, but kind words from my coworkers and superiors will keep me motivated and working hard.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "Where do you see yourself five years from now?", "answers": ["It's impossible to know where you will be in 5 years but you should assure the interviewer that, given all possible circumstances, you could see yourself as a long-term fit for their position.", "\"Ideally, five years from now, I would love to see myself growing into a more prominent leadership role within your organization. My career interests align very nicely with your company's goals which helps me to see a great long-term fit here.\"", "\"In 5 years I would like to be seen as an authority in our industry. I would like to be well-connected and trusted when it comes to my work here.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best thing that you can do when asked about your salary expectations is to be open and honest about what you are currently earning, and where you want to be in the future.", "\"I can share with you what I am currently earning, and where I would like to be in my next position. Currently, I am earning a base salary of $78K plus an annual bonus opportunity of an additional 10%. Last year my earnings were $85K, and I'd like to earn a bit above that in my next position.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities. I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "Tell me about an error or mistake you made because of a breakdown in communication from you or one of your team members.", "answers": ["On occasion, mistakes will happen, and communication will become broken. Talk to the interviewer about a time that this occurred in the workplace. How did you resolve the situation?", "\"I recall one instance where I misread an email from one of my subordinates. The punctuation was incorrect, and I read it in in a dire tone rather than in a positive one, as it was intended. After a tense conversation, the employee clarified her intention, and it seems I was mistaken. She and I agreed to exercise verbal communication on a regular basis to avoid a similar situation from happening again.\"", "\"We recently had a missing link in communications to one of our vendors, who we signed on to provide a large service.  They were not aware of a change in the agreement which cost the company wasted time, resources and money.  We were able to identify the breakdown in communication and change the process to ensure it does not happen again.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "What do you know about our company culture?", "answers": ["Company culture and fit is a crucial factor when considering a career move. Assure the interviewer that you have put thought, research, and consideration of how the company culture will work for you.", "\"I have researched your company through your social media channels and on glassdoor.com. Your employees have great things to say, and overall it seems that you have fun while you work. I am looking forward to joining an organization, like yours, that is upbeat and thoughtful with an eye on helping the community at the same time.\"", "\"I read many positive reviews online about your organization and company culture.  You offer great incentives to keep people motivated, and it seems to be the type of fast-paced environment that values innovation and performance.  My type of place!\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "How many days were you absent from work last year?", "answers": ["A part of being a diligent employee is to ensure that you are always on time and present when expected. It's great to even be 10 minutes early rather than just showing up right on the dot. Talk to the interviewer about your attendance.", "\"I had zero unexcused absences last year. In total, I took 12 vacation days out of my 15 allotted days. I was sick just 2, and a note from my Doctor accompanied those. Once I was late due to a terrible snow storm, and I always try to be 10 minutes early for my shift.\"", "\"I think I missed ten days, counting vacation time. Of those, five were for my vacation.  For three days, I was excused under a doctor's note.  The other two absences were pre-approved family days.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "Company ABC is asking for 8 years of industry experience and you have just 5. Why do you think you are qualified for this position?", "answers": ["To many employers, the number of years' experience is flexible - so long as you have the results to show for the years that you do have. Talk to the interviewer about your major career successes. This question is the time to sell yourself. Make no apologies for your lack of years!", "\"Although I have five years' experience vs. eight years' experience I can do this job well. In my previous role, I was outperforming colleagues who had 12  years of experience. To me, it's all about drive and ability to be a quick study. I have all of these qualities and more.\"", "\"Along with my five years working in this industry, I have worked in related industries my entire career. Also, I hope that my graduate degree gives me a little boost in experience over the required undergraduate degree.\""]}, {"topic": "Wholesale+and+Distribution", "question": "How do you make tough decisions knowing they will affect your entire team?", "answers": ["It can be difficult to make challenging decisions when you know that your entire team will be affected. Your ability to be decisive and diplomatic will make all the difference! \n\nIf you take a more team-oriented approach, share how you collaborate with the group by inviting everyone to discuss their opinions and come to a census. If you prefer to take charge of these situations, share how you step up to a decision while still taking everyone's needs and feelings into consideration.", "\"Leaders are truly set apart by their ability to make tough decisions respectfully and diplomatically. Last year we had to lay off 25% of our sales team. I knew that there would be feelings hurt and it was challenging to do. I got through it by reminding myself that I am the leader for a reason. I needed to trust my judgment but still be able to justify my decisions in the end. Many times when tough choices are in front of me, I will back up my gut feeling with data analysis. If the data supports my intuition, I know what the answer or decision needs to be.\"", "\"I believe that when you are working with a team, it is important to bring any questions or situations to the team before making a decision. Everyone should have input; however, the leader needs to be able to pull the trigger on all decisions in the end.\""]}]